<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN" "journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.3" xml:lang="EN">
<front>
<journal-meta>
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Mar. Sci.</journal-id>
<journal-title>Frontiers in Marine Science</journal-title>
<abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Front. Mar. Sci.</abbrev-journal-title>
<issn pub-type="epub">2296-7745</issn>
<publisher>
<publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name>
</publisher>
</journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fmars.2022.906383</article-id>
<article-categories>
<subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
<subject>Marine Science</subject>
<subj-group>
<subject>Original Research</subject>
</subj-group>
</subj-group>
</article-categories>
<title-group>
<article-title>Molecular Phylogeny of the Genus <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (Nemertea: Monostilifera: Cratenemertidae) and Descriptions of 10 New Species, With Notes on Small Body Size in a Newly Discovered Clade</article-title>
</title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
<name>
<surname>Hookabe</surname>
<given-names>Natsumi</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref>
<xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn001">
<sup>*</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1739488"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname>
<given-names>Hiroshi</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1863678"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname>
<given-names>Alexei V.</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">
<sup>3</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1550219"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Jimi</surname>
<given-names>Naoto</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4">
<sup>4</sup>
</xref>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5">
<sup>5</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/743695"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Hasegawa</surname>
<given-names>Naohiro</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff6">
<sup>6</sup>
</xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kohtsuka</surname>
<given-names>Hisanori</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff7">
<sup>7</sup>
</xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Okanishi</surname>
<given-names>Masanori</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff7">
<sup>7</sup>
</xref>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff8">
<sup>8</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1863634"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Tani</surname>
<given-names>Kenichiro</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff9">
<sup>9</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1058839"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Fujiwara</surname>
<given-names>Yoshihiro</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff10">
<sup>10</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1294961"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Tsuchida</surname>
<given-names>Shinji</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff10">
<sup>10</sup>
</xref>
<uri xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1765876"/>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Ueshima</surname>
<given-names>Rei</given-names>
</name>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref>
</contrib>
</contrib-group>
<aff id="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
<institution>Department of Biological Sciences, Graduate School of Science, The University of Tokyo</institution>, <addr-line>Tokyo</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
<institution>Faculty of Science, Hokkaido University</institution>, <addr-line>Sapporo</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff3">
<sup>3</sup>
<institution>Zhirmunsky National Scientific Centre of Marine Biology, Far Eastern Branch, Russian Academy of Sciences</institution>, <addr-line>Vladivostok</addr-line>, <country>Russia</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff4">
<sup>4</sup>
<institution>Sugashima Marine Biological Laboratory, Graduate School of Science, Nagoya University</institution>, <addr-line>Toba</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff5">
<sup>5</sup>
<institution>Centre for Marine and Coastal Studies, Universiti Sains Malaysia</institution>, <addr-line>Penang</addr-line>, <country>Malaysia</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff6">
<sup>6</sup>
<institution>Department of Natural History Sciences, Graduate School of Science, Hokkaido University</institution>, <addr-line>Sapporo</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff7">
<sup>7</sup>
<institution>Misaki Marine Biological Station, School of Science, The University of Tokyo</institution>, <addr-line>Miura</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff8">
<sup>8</sup>
<institution>Faculty of Human Environmental Studies, Hiroshima Shudo University</institution>, <addr-line>Hiroshima</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff9">
<sup>9</sup>
<institution>Department of Geology and Palaeontology, National Museum of Nature and Science</institution>, <addr-line>Tsukuba</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<aff id="aff10">
<sup>10</sup>
<institution>Research Institute for Global Change (RIGC), Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology (JAMSTEC)</institution>, <addr-line>Yokosuka</addr-line>, <country>Japan</country>
</aff>
<author-notes>
<fn fn-type="edited-by">
<p>Edited by: Jin Sun, Ocean University of China, China</p>
</fn>
<fn fn-type="edited-by">
<p>Reviewed by: Jose Alfaya, CONICET Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a de Organismos Marinos (IBIOMAR), Argentina; Aida Verdes, Department of Biodiversity and Evolutionary Biology, National Museum of Natural Sciences, Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), Spain; Fernando &#xc1;ngel Fern&#xe1;ndez-&#xc1;lvarez, Institute of Marine Sciences, Spanish National Research Council (CSIC), Spain</p>
</fn>
<fn fn-type="corresp" id="fn001">
<p>*Correspondence: Natsumi Hookabe, <email xlink:href="mailto:sofeechan312@gmail.com">sofeechan312@gmail.com</email>
</p>
</fn>
<fn fn-type="other" id="fn002">
<p>This article was submitted to Marine Evolutionary Biology, Biogeography and Species Diversity, a section of the journal Frontiers in Marine Science</p>
</fn>
</author-notes>
<pub-date pub-type="epub">
<day>26</day>
<month>07</month>
<year>2022</year>
</pub-date>
<pub-date pub-type="collection">
<year>2022</year>
</pub-date>
<volume>9</volume>
<elocation-id>906383</elocation-id>
<history>
<date date-type="received">
<day>28</day>
<month>03</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date>
<date date-type="accepted">
<day>16</day>
<month>05</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date>
</history>
<permissions>
<copyright-statement>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Hookabe, Kajihara, Chernyshev, Jimi, Hasegawa, Kohtsuka, Okanishi, Tani, Fujiwara, Tsuchida and Ueshima</copyright-statement>
<copyright-year>2022</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Hookabe, Kajihara, Chernyshev, Jimi, Hasegawa, Kohtsuka, Okanishi, Tani, Fujiwara, Tsuchida and Ueshima</copyright-holder>
<license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">
<p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</p>
</license>
</permissions>
<abstract>
<p>Nemerteans, or ribbon worms, have been reported from intertidal to hadal depths, often showing bathymetrically wide distribution in genus levels. Although current nemertean systematics practices require to provide DNA sequences and infer phylogenetic relationships with suitable molecular markers, previous molecular systematics on nemerteans are mostly biased toward shallow-water species. Members in the genus <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> occur worldwide, from tropical to polar waters and intertidal to bathyal waters. Molecular phylogenetic studies are scarce for the genus; only six shallow-water species of 18 species in the genus were subject to molecular phylogeny. Thus, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> is one candidate that needs to be assessed by genetic approaches. In this study, we performed molecular phylogenetic analyses using 59 specimens in 23 species based on partial sequences of two mitochondrial (16S rRNA and cytochrome c oxidase subunit I) and three nuclear gene markers (18S rRNA, 28S rRNA, and histone H3). Our extensive sampling from intertidal to bathyal waters in the Northwest Pacific significantly updated the fauna of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> in this region from four to 17 species. We herein establish 10 new species and provide an updated species list concisely summarizing all the congeners known from the world. Our phylogenetic tree indicated three major lineages within the genus (herein referred to as &#x201c;Clade A, B, and C&#x201d;), each presumably characterized by the combination of morphological characters in the head region. Members in Clade A are: <italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> (Johnston, 1837), <italic>Nipponnemertes ogumai</italic> (Yamaoka, 1947), and several unidentified congeners, characterized by having demarcated head without cephalic patches; members in Clade B are: <italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov., and <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov., species having demarcated head with cephalic patches; members in Clade C are: <italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov., <italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov., and two unidentified forms collected off Jogashima (Japan) and Guam (USA), species with non-demarcated head lacking cephalic patches. Furthermore, we discuss the evolution of remarkably small body size retained among Clade C.</p>
</abstract>
<kwd-group>
<kwd>Hoplonemertea</kwd>
<kwd>ROV</kwd>
<kwd>Nemertea</kwd>
<kwd>systematics</kwd>
<kwd>ribbon worm</kwd>
<kwd>SCUBA</kwd>
</kwd-group>
<contract-num rid="cn001">21J14807, 25650133, 26282067, 26304011, 20H03304, 20K06780</contract-num>
<contract-sponsor id="cn001">Japan Society for the Promotion of Science London<named-content content-type="fundref-id">10.13039/501100000646</named-content>
</contract-sponsor>
<counts>
<fig-count count="16"/>
<table-count count="4"/>
<equation-count count="0"/>
<ref-count count="90"/>
<page-count count="36"/>
<word-count count="17245"/>
</counts>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<sec id="s1" sec-type="intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<p>Ribbon worms (phylum Nemertea) are commonly known as predators or scavengers in a wide variety of marine, freshwater, and terrestrial ecosystems (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B68">McDermott &amp; Roe, 1985</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B80">Thiel &amp; Kruse, 2001</xref>). The phylum currently contains around 1300 species (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">Chernyshev, 2021</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B49">Kajihara, 2021a</xref>), of which about 594 species in 127 genera are members in the order Monostilifera (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">Kajihara, 2021b</xref>). The Monostilifera can be divided into the suborders Cratenemertea and Eumonostilifera chiefly by a combination of three characters: the arrangement of the rhynchocoel musculature (a wickerwork of longitudinal and circular muscle fibres in Cratenemertea as well as in some Eumonostililfera <italic>vs</italic> separate inner longitudinal and outer circular muscle layers in Eumonostilifera), the vascular plug (single plug in Cratenemertea <italic>vs</italic> variously 0&#x2013;2 plugs in Eumonostilifera), and the position of the cerebral organs (mostly extending behind brain in Cratenemertea <italic>vs</italic> at most to the brain region in Eumonostilifera) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">Chernyshev, 2021</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">Kajihara, 2021b</xref>). While these taxonomic characters seem to have evolved homoplastically (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">Kajihara, 2021b</xref>), the distinction between Cratenemertea and Eumonostilifera is supported by molecular phylogenetic analyses based on multiple loci in nuclear and mitochondrial genomes (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B60">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>).</p>
<p>Molecular systematics within Cratenemertea is still in progress. Although 28 species in three families have been recognized in this taxon, phylogenetic relationships within Cratenemertea are not well resolved due to a lack of molecular data. So far, species in two genera, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall, 1989</xref> and <italic>Uniporus</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">Brinkmann, 1914&#x2013;1915a</xref>, and unidentified specimens collected from the Far Eastern seas of Russia, have been included in molecular phylogeny (e.g., <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2018</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev and Polyakova, 2019</xref>). Recent molecular phylogenetic analyses suggest that &#x2018;Cratenemertea sp. 25DS&#x2019; (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>) and &#x2018;Cratenemertidae sp. IZ-45644&#x2019; (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>) are the sister taxon to <italic>Uniporus</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>). &#x2018;Cratenemertea sp. 25DS&#x2019; is likely to be a planktonic juvenile of &#x2018;Cratenemertidae sp. IZ-45644&#x2019; (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>). Although &#x2018;Cratenemertea sp. 25DS&#x2019; is morphologically similar to <italic>Achoronemertes scorebyi</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler, 1934</xref>) and <italic>Korotkevitschia pelagica</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B55">Korotkevitsch, 1961</xref>) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>), a comparison of both morphological and molecular data is required for accurate species identification.</p>    <p>Another issue that needs to be investigated with the molecular approach is the generic distinction between <italic>Cratenemertes</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B28">Friedrich, 1955</xref> and <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>. <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B28">Friedrich (1955)</xref> established <italic>Cratenemertes</italic> for a species originally described by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">B&#xfc;rger (1890)</xref>, <italic>Amphiporus amboinensis</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">B&#xfc;rger, 1890</xref>; in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">Friedrich (1968)</xref>, the generic name was attributed to species with a small cerebral organ posteriorly fused with dorsal cerebral ganglia. Whether smaller cerebral organs in <italic>Cratenemertes</italic>&#x2014;the only difference between the two genera&#x2014;are a phylogenetic signal or not need to be verified with molecular data.</p>
<p>Species in the genus <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>&#x2014;18 are currently recognized as valid&#x2014;represent the majority of Cratenemertea (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">Gonzalez-Cueto et&#xa0;al., 2017</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">Kajihara, 2021b</xref>). They are marine benthic, usually feeding on small crustaceans such as amphipods (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6">Brunberg, 1964</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">Berg, 1972</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B65">McDermott, 1984</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B66">McDermott, 1993</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B67">McDermott, 1997</xref>) and caridean shrimps (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>) by sucking out body fluid and internal tissue of those prey organisms. <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> was established by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">Friedrich (1968)</xref> for the seven nominal species <italic>Amphiporus bergendali</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B32">Gering, 1912</xref>, <italic>Amphiporus drepanophoroides</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">Griffin, 1898</xref>, <italic>Amphiporus pacificus</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>, <italic>Amphiporus occidentalis</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>, <italic>Amphiporus punctatulus</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>, <italic>Cratenemertes danae</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">Friedrich, 1957</xref>, and <italic>Cratenemertes madagascarensis</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer, 1965</xref> without type designation, and thus was unavailable under Article 13.3 of the International Code of Zoological Nomenclature (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B43">International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature, 1999</xref>). To make <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> nomenclaturally available, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall (1989)</xref> designated <italic>A. drepanophoroides</italic> as the type species and provided a morphological diagnosis for the genus; the authorship of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> is thus ascribed to <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall (1989)</xref>. Phylogenetic relationships among some members of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> were inferred by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al. (2015)</xref>, where four described&#x2014;<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe, 1901</xref>), <italic>Nipponnemertes ogumai</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B88">Yamaoka, 1947</xref>), <italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">Johnston, 1837</xref>), and <italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)&#x2014;and two undescribed congeners&#x2014;<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1 (MCZ DNA105622) and <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2 (MCZ DNA105589) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>)&#x2014;were analysed. The resulting tree indicated that the six species were divided into two groups, which seemed to be characterized by the presence and absence of a cephalic patch (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>); however, it has never been confirmed based on a more comprehensive dataset.</p>
<p>From the Northwest Pacific in eastern Asia, including the Sea of Okhotsk, the Sea of Japan, and the East and South China Seas, four species of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> have been recorded: <italic>Nipponnemertes arenaria</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B83">Ushakov, 1927</xref>), <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>, <italic>N. ogumai</italic>, and <italic>N. punctatula</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B47">Kajihara, 2007</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B48">Kajihara, 2017</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B13">Chernyshev, 2020</xref>). Besides, several authors reported unidentified forms of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> from Japanese (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89">Yamaoka, 2005</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B48">Kajihara, 2017</xref>), Vietnamese (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B12">Chernyshev, 2016</xref>), and Far East Russian waters (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B13">Chernyshev, 2020</xref>), suggesting there is hidden nemertean diversity.</p>
<p>With the advent of molecular tools&#x2014;DNA barcoding and molecular phylogeny&#x2014;in monostiliferan systematics (e.g., <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B60">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">Kvist et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B62">Leasi et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B41">Hookabe et&#xa0;al., 2020</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B40">Hookabe et&#xa0;al., 2021</xref>), we are now in a position to obtain a more accurate picture of the species diversity. Some of the diagnostic characters traditionally used in monostiliferan taxonomy are often ambiguous and thus need to be revisited with molecular phylogeny. In the present study, we describe 10 new species of the genus from Japanese and Far East Russian waters. Since previous studies on molecular phylogenetic study in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> were biased toward shallow-water species (e.g., <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>) despite the bathymetrically wide distribution of this taxon, we extensively sampled specimens from intertidal to bathyal waters by various methods: by hand for intertidal species, SCUBA, dredging, sledging, and a remotely operated vehicle (ROV) equipped with a slurp gun. In the description part, histological observation (including cerebral organ, which is an important character for distinguishing <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> from <italic>Cratenemertes</italic>) was performed to characterize the internal morphology of each taxon. Using molecular data obtained from the newly discovered species and described species from Japanese and Far East Russian waters, phylogenetic analyses based on partial sequences of nuclear and mitochondrial genes are performed to assess phylogenetic relationships as well as species boundaries within the genus.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s2" sec-type="materials|methods">
<title>Materials and Methods</title>
<sec id="s2_1">
<title>Taxon Sampling and Morphological Examination</title>
<p>In the present study, we collected cratenemertids from Japanese and Far East Russian waters in 2014&#x2013;2021 by multiple methods (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1</bold>
</xref> and <xref ref-type="table" rid="T1">
<bold>Table&#xa0;1</bold>
</xref>). Specimens were photographed with digital still cameras NIKON D5600 (NIKON, Japan) or OM-D E-M1 Mark II (Olympus, Japan) while they were alive. Worms were anaesthetized in 7.5% MgCl<sub>2</sub> and gently placed between a slide glass and cover slip with a drop of anaesthetic solution so that ocelli and stylet apparatus could be observed under a light microscope. Afterwards, worms were picked up from the slides and the posterior tips were preserved in 99% ethanol for DNA extraction while the rest of the body was pre-fixed in 10% formalin in seawater, then post-fixed in Bouin&#x2019;s fluid for 24 hours, and transferred to 70% ethanol. For histological preparation, samples preserved in 70% ethanol were dehydrated in a series of ethanol solutions (70%, 80%, 90%, 95%, and 99% ethanol), cleared in xylene, and embedded in Surgipath Paraplast paraffin (Leica, Germany). Paraffin blocks were serially sectioned at 7 &#xb5;m thickness and stained with Mallory&#x2019;s trichrome method (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B33">Gibson, 1994</xref>).</p>
<fig id="f1" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;1</label>
<caption>
<p>Sampling sites of specimens used in the present study. <bold>(A)</bold> Overview map. <bold>(B)</bold> Collection sites in Noto, Japan. <bold>(C)</bold> Collection sites in Kanto region and adjacent areas, Japan, including Tateyama, off Jogashima, and off Izu Peninsula. <bold>(D)</bold> Collection sites around Sugashima, Japan. <bold>(E)</bold> <italic>In-situ</italic> photographs of <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov., Koganezaki, Shizuoka, Japan. <bold>(F)</bold> <italic>In-situ</italic> photograph of <italic>N. ganahai</italic> sp. nov., crawling near an octopus brooding eggs (circle with broken line), off Ofunato, Iwate, Japan. <bold>(G)</bold> Close-up of <italic>N. ganahai</italic> sp. nov. in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1F</bold>
</xref>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g001.tif"/>
</fig>
<table-wrap id="T1" position="float">
<label>Table&#xa0;1</label>
<caption>
<p>Specimen collection information with ICHUM and GenBank accession numbers.</p>
</caption>
<table frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="left">Species</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Sample ID</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Collection location</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Coordinate</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Depth</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Collection method</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="2" align="center">Collector(s)</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">Collection date</th>
<th valign="top" rowspan="2" align="center">ICHUM number</th>
<th valign="top" colspan="6" align="center">GenBank accession number</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<th valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">COI</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">16S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">18S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">28S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">H3</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SG02</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima, Mie, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Gill net</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe, N. Jimi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">3 Nov. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8315</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357606</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356061</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356033</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356046</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382008</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.448&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;32.603&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.29N, 139&#xb0;32.30&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">182&#x2013;250 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Feb. 2015</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357620</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356063</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382011</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG02</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.448&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;32.603&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.29N, 139&#xb0;32.30&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">182&#x2013;250 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Feb. 2015</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357598</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356053</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356027</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356038</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382001</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG03</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.448&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;32.603&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.29N, 139&#xb0;32.30&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">198&#x2013;274 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Feb. 2015</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357619</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356062</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356047</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382010</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KC01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Tosa Bay, Kochi, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">33&#xb0;18.452&#x2019;N, 133&#xb0;35.829&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">100-m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sledge, R/V Toyohata-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">24 Jul. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357615</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KC02</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Tosa Bay, Kochi, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">33&#xb0;18.452&#x2019;N, 133&#xb0;35.829&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">100-m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sledge, R/V Toyohata-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">24 Jul. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357616</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KC03</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Tosa Bay, Kochi, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">33&#xb0;18.452&#x2019;N, 133&#xb0;35.829&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">100-m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sledge, R/V Toyohata-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">24 Jul. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357617</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KC04</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Tosa Bay, Kochi, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">33&#xb0;18.452&#x2019;N, 133&#xb0;35.829&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">100-m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sledge, R/V Toyohata-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">24 Jul. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357618</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">NT01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto, Ishikawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">37&#xb0;18.239&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.091&#x2019;E&#x2013;37&#xb0;1.222&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.166&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">71.2&#x2013;79.2 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Aosagi</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">20 Nov. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8316</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357604</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON3560567</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356030</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356042</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382004</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG04</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.402&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;32.857&#x2032;E&#x2013;139&#xb0;32.504&#x2032;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">116&#x2013;211 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">31 Jun. 2020</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8317</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357608</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG05</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.402&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;32.857E&#x2032;&#x2013;139&#xb0;32.504&#x2032;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">116&#x2013;211 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">31 Jun. 2020</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357609</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG06</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;08.402&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;32.857&#x2032;E&#x2013;139&#xb0;32.504&#x2032;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">116&#x2013;211 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">31 Jun. 2020</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357610</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CL01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Ofunato, Iwate, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">39&#xb0;00.726 N&#x2032;, 142&#xb0;21.971&#x2032;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">985 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Slurp gun, ROV <italic>Crambon</italic>, R/V <italic>Kaimei</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Jul. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON391164</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG07</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;7.454&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;33.666&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;7.623N, 139&#xb0;33.100&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">139&#x2013;222 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Mar. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357607</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG08</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;7.419&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.112&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;7.325N, 139&#xb0;33.572&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">144&#x2013;240 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Mar. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357611</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG09</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;7.419&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.112&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;7.325N, 139&#xb0;33.572&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">144&#x2013;240 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 Mar. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357612</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG39</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">80 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Gill net</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kohtsuka</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">10 Apr. 2012</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357625</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356067</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356035</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356050</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382016</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG42</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.456&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.900&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">83 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kohtsuka</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">25 Apr. 2012</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8318</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357624</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356034</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382015</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG88</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.42&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.22N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">87&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Feb. 2014</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8319</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357597</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356052</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356037</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG89</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.42&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.22N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">87&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Feb. 2014</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357623</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356066</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356049</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382014</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG93</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.42&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.22N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">87&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Feb. 2014</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357622</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356065</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382013</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG94</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.42&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.22N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">87&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Feb. 2014</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357621</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356064</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356048</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382012</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KZ</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koza, Wakayama, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SCUBA</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hasegawa</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">11 May. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8320</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center"/>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356059</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356032</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356044</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382006</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">TK</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Shimoda, Shizuoka, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">34&#xb0;28.650&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;11.380&#x2019;E&#x2013;34&#xb0;28.559&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;11.474&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">98&#x2013;120 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Tsukuba II</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">25 Mar. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8321</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357603</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356056</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356029</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356041</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">RU1</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Vostok bay, RU</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">5 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Snorkel</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">A.V. Chernyshev</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">11 Aug. 2015</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">MIMB43013</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211492</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">MN205510</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211395</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211445</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205467</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">NT12</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto, Ishikawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">37&#xb0;18.239&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.091&#x2019;E&#x2013;37&#xb0;1.222&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.166&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">70&#x2013;91 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Aosagi</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">20 Nov. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8322</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357599</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">NT13</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto, Ishikawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">37&#xb0;18.239&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.091&#x2019;E&#x2013;37&#xb0;1.222&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.166&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">70&#x2013;91 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Aosagi</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">20 Nov. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8323</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357600</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KG01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koganezaki, Shizuoka, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SCUBA</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">M. Okanishi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">21 Oct. 2020</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8324</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357605</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356058</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356031</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356043</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382005</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KG02</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koganezaki, Shizuoka, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">8 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SCUBA</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Jimi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">6 Jan. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8325</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">KG03</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koganezaki, Shizuoka, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">7 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SCUBA</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">6 Jan. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8326</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">NT10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto, Ishikawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">37&#xb0;18.239&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.091&#x2019;E&#x2013;37&#xb0;1.222&#x2019;N, 137&#xb0;16.166&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">70&#x2013;91 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Aosagi</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">20 Nov. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8327</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357602</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356055</td>
<td valign="top" align="center"/>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356040</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382003</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">TT</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Tateyama, Chiba, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">By hand</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">R. Yoshida</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">13 Jun. 2018</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8328</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357613</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SG03</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima, Mie, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">By hand</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Jimi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">24 Jun. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8329</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357626</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SG01</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Toba bay, Mie, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10&#x2013;15 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Gill net</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe, N. Jimi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">3 Nov. 2021</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8330</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356060</td>
<td valign="top" align="center"/>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356045</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382007</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SD</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sado, Niigata, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">SCUBA</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Jimi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">26 Sep. 2019</td>
<td valign="top" align="left"/>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357614</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG15</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">35&#xb0;8.42&#x2019;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2019;E&#x2013;35&#xb0;8.22N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2019;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">87&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">H. Kajihara</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">19 Feb. 2014</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8331</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357589</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356051</td>
<td valign="top" align="center"/>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356036</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382009</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">JG16</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima, Kanagawa, JP</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">5&#xb0;08.402&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;32.857&#x2032;&#x2013;139&#xb0;32.504&#x2032;E</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">116&#x2013;211 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Biological dredge, R/V Rinkai-maru</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="left">N. Hookabe</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">31 Jun. 2020</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ICHUM8332</td>
<td valign="top" colspan="2" align="center">ON357601</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356054</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356028</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON356039</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ON382002</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
</sec>
<sec id="s2_2">
<title>DNA Extraction, PCR Amplification, and Sequencing</title>
<p>Total DNA was extracted using the DNeasy Blood &amp;Tissue Kit (Qiagen, Germany) according to the manufacturer&#x2019;s protocol. Each partial sequence was amplified with primer pairs summarized in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T2">
<bold>Table&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref> according to the following PCR protocol: preheating at 94&#xb0;C for 2 min; 35 cycles of 94&#xb0;C for 40 s, 52&#xb0;C for 60&#x2013;75 s, and 72&#xb0;C for 60 s; then a final extension at 72&#xb0;C for 7 min. PCR products were purified using Exo-SAP-IT (Thermo Fisher Scientific, USA). Sequencing reaction was performed with BigDye Terminator ver. 3.1 Cycle Sequencing Kit (Thermo Fisher Scientific, USA); for partial sequences of 18S rRNA (18S) and 28S rRNA (28S), internal primers listed in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T2">
<bold>Table&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref> were additionally used. The resulting dye-labelled products were purified with the EDTA/ethanol precipitation method and sent to GENEWIZ (Tokyo, Japan) for nucleotide sequencing. Sequences newly obtained in this study have been deposited in DNA Data Bank of Japan (DDBJ) under accession numbers listed in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T1">
<bold>Table&#xa0;1</bold>
</xref>. Type and voucher specimens have been deposited in Invertebrate Collection of the Hokkaido University Museum (ICHUM), Sapporo, Japan and Zoological Museum of Far East Federal University, Vladivostok, Russia.</p>
<table-wrap id="T2" position="float">
<label>Table&#xa0;2</label>
<caption>
<p>List of primers used for the phylogenetic analyses in the present study.</p>
</caption>
<table frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="left">Locus</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Primer</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Sequence (5&#xb4;&#x2013;3&#xb4;)</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Reference</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">16S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ar-L</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CGCCTGTTTATCAAAAACAT</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B69">Palumbi et&#xa0;al. (1991)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">16S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">br-H</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CCGGTCTGAACTCAGATCACGT</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B69">Palumbi et&#xa0;al. (1991)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">COI</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">LCO1490</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">GGTCAACAAATCATAAAGATATTGG</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B27">Folmer et&#xa0;al. (1994)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">COI</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">HCO2198</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">TAAACTTCAGGGTGACCAAAAAATCA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B27">Folmer et&#xa0;al. (1994)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">1F</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">TACCTGGTTGATCCTGCCAGTAG</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">Giribet et&#xa0;al. (1996)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">5R</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CTTGGCAAATGCTTTCGC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">Giribet et&#xa0;al. (1996)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">3F</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">GTTCGATTCCGGAGAGGGA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">Giribet et&#xa0;al. (1996)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">18Sbi</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">GAGTCTCGTTCGTTATCGGA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B87">Whiting et&#xa0;al. (1997)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">S2.0</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">ATGGTTGCAAAGCTGAAAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left" style="background-color:#ffffff">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B87">Whiting et&#xa0;al. (1997)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">18S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">9R</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">GATCCTTCCGCAGGTTCACCTAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">Giribet et&#xa0;al. (1996)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">LSU5</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ACCCGCTGAAYTTAAGCA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B64">Littlewood (1994)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">LSU3</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">TCCTGAGGGAAACTTCGG</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B64">Littlewood (1994)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">D2f</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CTTTGAAGAGAGAGTTC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B64">Littlewood (1994)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">28Z</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CTTGGTCCGTGTTTCAAGAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B39">Hillis &amp; Dixon (1991)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sa</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">GACCCGTCTTGAAACACGGA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B87">Whiting et&#xa0;al. (1997)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">28S rRNA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">rd5b</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">CCACAGCGCCAGTTCTGCTTAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B75">Schwendinger and Giribet (2005)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">H3</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">aF</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ATGGCTCGTACCAAGCAGAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B22">Colgan et&#xa0;al. (1998)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">H3</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">aR</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">ATATCCTTRGGCATRATRGTGAC</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B22">Colgan et&#xa0;al. (1998)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
</sec>
<sec id="s2_3">
<title>Sequence Alignment and Phylogenetic Analyses</title>
<p>Sequencing chromatographs were checked and edited with GeneStudio Pro ver. 2.2 (GeneStudio, Inc., USA). Sequences newly obtained in this study were combined with sequences available in GenBank listed in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T3">
<bold>Table&#xa0;3</bold>
</xref>. For 16S, 18S, and 28S, data sets were aligned by MAFFT ver. 7 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B53">Katoh &amp; Standley, 2013</xref>) using the automatically selected strategy L-INS-i. After being aligned with ClustalW algorithm (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B82">Thompson et&#xa0;al., 1994</xref>) implemented in MEGA ver. 7 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B58">Kumar et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>), COI and H3 sequences were checked by translating into amino acids to see if they did not contain stop codons. Ambiguous sites were removed by Gblocks ver. 0.91b (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">Castresana, 2000</xref>) under a less stringent option; a 657-bp sequence for COI, a 458-bp for16S, a 1740-bp for 18S, a 1221-bp for 28S, and a 330-bp for H3 finally remained. After tree topology is checked for each marker and consistent with each other, partial sequences of COI, 16S, 18S, 28S, and H3 were concatenated using MEGA ver. 7.</p>
<table-wrap id="T3" position="float">
<label>Table&#xa0;3</label>
<caption>
<p>GenBank accession numbers of eumonostiliferans except species herein described, which are used in the molecular phylogenetic analyses.</p>
</caption>
<table frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="left">Species</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">16S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">COI</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">18S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">28S</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">H3</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Source</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes arenaria</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211491</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205509</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211394</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211444</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205466</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2019)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AJ436799</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AJ436909</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AJ436854</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AJ436961</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B81">Thollesson &amp; Norenburg (2003)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> E3F9</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197269</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197602</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Hiebert &amp; Maslakova (unpublished)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> E3G1</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197270</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197603</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Hiebert &amp; Maslakova (unpublished)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> E3G2</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197271</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197604</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Hiebert &amp; Maslakova (unpublished)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> E3G3</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU197605</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Hiebert &amp; Maslakova (unpublished)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes incainca</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KX879856</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">Gonzalez-Cueto et&#xa0;al. (2017)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ogumai</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AB921008</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AB920927</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AB921009</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">AB921010</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al. (2015)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277625</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ848597</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF293012</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ856871</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277704</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al. (2012)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar0127</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU839800</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar0132</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU839804</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar0133</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU839805</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar0134</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU839806</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar0383</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU839981</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1161</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697764</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1162</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697765</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1163</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697767</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1164</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697761</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1165</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697763</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1449</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697762</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> NemBar1287</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP697766</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU230292</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU230295</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU230293</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KU230294</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B62">Leasi et&#xa0;al. (2016)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105622</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277624</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ848598</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF293020</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ856872</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277703</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al. (2012)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105589</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277623</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ848599</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF293019</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ856870</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277705</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al. (2012)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">Cratenemertidae sp. Guam</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211490</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205508</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211393</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211443</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205465</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2019)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" colspan="7" align="left">Outgroup</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">Cratenemertidae sp. IZ-45644</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP270854</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP270877</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP270804</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KP270829</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">Kvist et&#xa0;al. (2015)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">Cratenemertea sp. 25DS</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512058</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512127</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512086</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512111</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2018)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Malacobdella grossa</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ848591</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ848591</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF293015</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">HQ856882</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">JF277700</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al. (2012)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nemertovema hadalis</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KY296891</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KY296912</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KY296895</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KY296903</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">KY296921</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2018)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Oerstedia oculata</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211495</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205512</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211398</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211448</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205469</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2019)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Oerstedia phoresiae</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211496</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205513</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211399</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN211449</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MN205470</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2019)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Proamphiporus kaimeiae</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">LC505452</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">LC505451</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">LC520132</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">LC505453</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">LC520133</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B41">Hookabe et&#xa0;al. (2020)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Tetrastemma cupido</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">OK428649</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">OK414013</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">OK428689</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">OK428648</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2014;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B40">Hookabe et&#xa0;al. (2021)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Uniporus alisae</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512053</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512121</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512080</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512105</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">MF512147</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova (2018)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<p>To infer phylogenetic relationships among cratenemertids examined in the present study, molecular phylogenetic trees were reconstructed based on maximum-likelihood (ML) and Bayesian inference (BI) analyses. The ML analysis was performed with RaxML ver. 8.0.0 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B76">Stamatakis, 2014</xref>) under GTR + G + I selected as an optimum nucleotide substitution model by PartitionFinder ver. 2.1.1 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B61">Lanfear et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>) employing the greedy algorithm. Nodal support values were obtained from 1000 bootstrap pseudoreplicates. The BI tree was obtained using MrBayes ver. 3.2.3 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B74">Ronquist et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>) under GTR + G + I model selected by PartitionFinder ver. 2.1.1, launching two independent Metropolis-coupled analyses with four Markov chains for 10<sup>7</sup> generations and sampling every 100 generations from the chains. Run convergence was assessed by Tracer ver. 1.7 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B72">Rambaut et&#xa0;al., 2018</xref>).</p>
<p>Uncorrected pairwise genetic distances were calculated based on 657-bp COI by MEGA ver. 7.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s2_4">
<title>Species Delimitation Analyses</title>
<p>Using 658 bp of COI dataset, species delimitation analyses for <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> species with cephalic patches were performed employing three methods: Automatic Barcode Gap Discovery (ABGD) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B70">Puillandre et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>), Bayesian implementation of the PTP (bPTP) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B90">Zhang et&#xa0;al., 2013</xref>), and statistical parsimony (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B79">Templeton et&#xa0;al., 1992</xref>). The ABGD analyses was performed on the online server (<uri xlink:href="https://bioinfo.mnhn.fr/abi/public/abgd/abgdweb.html">https://bioinfo.mnhn.fr/abi/public/abgd/abgdweb.html</uri>) with default settings. The bPTP analyses were performed based on a ML tree generated by RaxML ver. 8.0.0 with the COI dataset. The statistical parsimony analysis was performed using the TCS algorithm (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B19">Clement et&#xa0;al., 2000</xref>) implemented in PopART (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B63">Leigh &amp; Bryant, 2015</xref>). Haplotype networks for individual loci were generated for visualizing relationships between haplotypes by using PopART.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="s3" sec-type="results">
<title>Results</title>
<sec id="s3_1">
<title>Phylogenetic Relationships Among <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>
</title>
<p>In the present study, we performed molecular phylogenetic analyses with 59 specimens of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>3</bold>
</xref>). Of these, 10 species turned out to be new to science and described based on external (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4</bold>
</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>6</bold>
</xref>) and internal morphology (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>16</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<fig id="f2" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;2</label>
<caption>
<p>Molecular phylogenetic tree reconstructed based on ML analyses using concatenated sequences of 16S rRNA, COI, 18S rRNA, 28S rRNA, and histone H3 genes, with illustrations showing general head morphology of species constituting each clade. Tree topology obtained by BI was generally identical with ML. Numbers near nodes indicate bootstrap support values (BS) generated by 1000 replicates and posterior probability (PP) of a separate partitioned BI analysis (BS/PP). Solid circles indicate full support values (100/1.00). Collection depths are provided in blue letters. acf, anterior cephalic furrow; cp, cephalic patch; cr, mid-dorsal cephalic ridge; oc, ocelli; pcf, posterior cephalic furrow; scg, secondary transverse groove.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g002.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f3" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;3</label>
<caption>
<p>Results of species delimitation analyses for <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> spp. in Clade <bold>(B). (A)</bold> A haplotype network generated by statistical parsimony analysis based on partial sequence (658 bp) of COI. Numbers of black bars correspond to the numbers of nucleotide substitutions between the haplotypes. <bold>(B)</bold> A ML tree based on 658 bp of COI. Vertical bars indicate the putative species delineated with TCS, ABGD, and bPTP methods. Solid circles indicate 100% of bootstrap values.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g003.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f4" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;4</label>
<caption>
<p>Images of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> spp., taken in life. <bold>(A, B)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic>, Sado (<bold>A</bold>, whole body; <bold>B</bold>, magnification of head). <bold>(C, D)</bold> <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1, off Jogashima (<bold>C</bold>, whole body; <bold>D</bold>, magnification of head). acf, anterior cephalic furrow; cr, mid-dorsal cephalic ridge. Scale bars: 1 cm <bold>(A, C)</bold>, 5 mm <bold>(B, D)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g004.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f5" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;5</label>
<caption>
<p>Images of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> spp., taken in life. <bold>(A)</bold> <italic>Nipponnemertes arenaria</italic>, Peter the Great Bay. <bold>
<italic>(</italic>B&#x2013;D)</bold> <italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov., Sugashima (<bold>B</bold>, whole body; <bold>C</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>D</bold>, ventral). <bold>(E&#x2013;H)</bold> <italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic> sp. nov., off Jogashima <bold>(E)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(F)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>(G)</bold>, ventral; <bold>(H)</bold>, lateral). <bold>(I&#x2013;K)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov., Koganezaki [<bold>(I)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(J)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>(K)</bold>, ventral]. <bold>(L&#x2013;P)</bold>, <italic>Nippponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov., Vostok Bay [<bold>(L)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(M)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal, living specimen; <bold>(N)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal, fixed specimen in formalin; <bold>(O)</bold>, magnification of head, ventral, living specimen; <bold>(P)</bold>, microphotograph of a live squeezed specimen, dorsal], <bold>(Q&#x2013;T)</bold>, <italic>Nippponnemertes punctatula</italic> [<bold>(Q)</bold>, Tateyama; <bold>(R, S)</bold>, Misaki; <bold>(T)</bold>, Sugashima]. Each arrowhead points to posterior cephalic furrows. acf, anterior cephalic furrow; cg, cerebral ganglia; co, cerebral organ; cr, mid-dorsal cephalic ridge; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; pp, proboscis pore; py, pylorus. Scale bars: 1 cm <bold>(A, B, L, S)</bold>, 5 mm <bold>(B, C, I, M, N, Q, T)</bold>; 2.5 mm <bold>(D)</bold>; 1 mm <bold>(E, R)</bold>; 500 &#x3bc;m <bold>(F&#x2013;H, J, K, O, P)</bold>; 1.5 mm <bold>(I)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g005.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f6" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;6</label>
<caption>
<p>Images of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> spp., taken in life. <bold>(A&#x2013;F)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov., collected off Ofunato <bold>(A&#x2013;C)</bold>, off Jogashima <bold>(D)</bold>, Tosa Bay <bold>(E&#x2013;G)</bold> [<bold>(A)</bold>, CL01, whole body; <bold>(B)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>(C)</bold>, lateral; <bold>(D)</bold>, JG01, whole body; <bold>(E)</bold>, KC01, whole body; <bold>(F)</bold>, magnification of head, ventral; <bold>(G)</bold>, microphotograph of a live squeezed specimen, dorsal]. <bold>(H&#x2013;J)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., Koza [<bold>(H)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(I)</bold>, magnification of head, ventral; <bold>(J)</bold>, dorsal]. <bold>(K, L)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov., off Izu [<bold>(K)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(L)</bold>, microphotograph of a live squeezed specimen, ventral]. <bold>(M)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> sp. nov. [<bold>(M)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(N)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>(O)</bold>, ventral]. <bold>(P, Q)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov., off Noto [<bold>(P)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(Q)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal]. <bold>(R&#x2013;U)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov., Sugashima [<bold>(R)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(S)</bold>, magnification of head, dorsal; <bold>(T)</bold>, microphotograph of a live squeezed specimen, dorsal; <bold>(U)</bold>, lateral blood vessel]. <bold>(V, W)</bold>, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2, off Jogashima [<bold>(V)</bold>, whole body; <bold>(W)</bold>, microphotograph of a live squeezed specimen, dorsal]. <bold>(X)</bold>, Cratemertidae sp. Guam, a live squeezed specimen. Each arrowhead points to posterior cephalic furrows. acf, anterior cephalic furrow; bv, blood vessel; cg, cerebral ganglia; pb, proboscis; pp, proboscis pore. Scale bars: 2 mm <bold>(A, D, E)</bold>, 1.5 mm <bold>(B)</bold>; 1 mm <bold>(C, H, M, P, V)</bold>; 500 &#x3bc;m <bold>(F, K, L, N, O, U)</bold>; 300 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G, J, Q, S)</bold>; 700 &#x3bc;m <bold>(I, R)</bold>; 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(T, W, X)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g006.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f7" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;7</label>
<caption>
<p>Stylet apparatus of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> spp., micrographs of squeezed live specimens.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g007.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f8" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;8</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Cephalic glands (arrowhead). <bold>(E)</bold> Precerebral vessels (arrowheads). <bold>(F)</bold> Precerebral septum. <bold>(G)</bold> Vascular plug (arrowhead). <bold>(H)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(I)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(J)</bold> Posterior region of cerebral ganglia. <bold>(K)</bold> Nephridial canals (black arrowheads) and mid-dorsal vessel (white box, a white arrowhead pointing to a blood cell in mid-dorsal vessel). <bold>(L)</bold> Testes. co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; mdv, mid-dorsal vessel; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; rc, rhynchocoel; rd, rhynchodaeum; st, stomach; sg, submuscular glands; te, testis; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A&#x2013;D, I)</bold>, 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(E, F, K)</bold>, 200 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G)</bold>, 150 &#x3bc;m <bold>(H, J)</bold>, 250 &#x3bc;m <bold>(L)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g008.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f9" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;9</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Anterior part of cephalic blood lacuna. <bold>(B)</bold> Rhynchodeal sphincter (arrowhead). <bold>(C)</bold> Cerebral organ (arrows indicate bifurcate canal of cerebral organ). <bold>(D)</bold> Collar. <bold>(E)</bold> Stomach. <bold>(F)</bold> Intestine. cg, cephalic glands; co, cerebral organ; col, collar; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; dvm, dorso-ventral muscles; es, esophagus; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; oc, ocelli; pv, precerebral vessel; rd, rhynchodaeum; st, stomach; vp, vascular plug. Scale bars: 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, C)</bold>, 200 &#x3bc;m <bold>(B, D&#x2013;F)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g009.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f10" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;10</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Cerebral glands. <bold>(E)</bold> Precerebral vessel (arrowhead). <bold>(F)</bold> Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(G)</bold> Mid-dorsal vessel (arrowehead). <bold>(H)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(I)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(J)</bold> Ventral cerebral commissure. <bold>(K)</bold> Nephridial tubules. <bold>(L)</bold> Intestine. co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; mdv, mid-dorsal vessel; nt, nephridial tubule; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; rc, rhynchocoel; rd, rhynchodaeum; sg, submuscular glands; st, stomach; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, C, D, E)</bold>, 25 &#x3bc;m <bold>(B, F)</bold>, 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G, J&#x2013;L)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(H)</bold>, 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(I)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g010.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f11" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;11</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (white arrowhead) and cephalic glands (black arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Precerebral vessels (arrowhead). <bold>(E)</bold> Cerebral organ opening (arrowhead). <bold>(F)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(G)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(H)</bold> Dorsal and ventral cerebral commissure. <bold>(I)</bold> Cerebral organ. <bold>(J)</bold> Posterior region of cerebral ganglia. <bold>(K)</bold> Ovaries. co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; mdv, mid-dorsal vessel; nt, nephridial tubule; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; ov, ovaries; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; py, pylorus; sg, submuscular glands; st, stomach; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, B, G)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(C&#x2013;E, J, K)</bold>, 150 &#x3bc;m <bold>(F)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(H, I)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g011.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f12" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;12</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Precerebral vessel (arrowhead) running above cerebral glands. <bold>(E)</bold> Mid-dorsal vessel. <bold>(F)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(G)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(H)</bold> Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(I)</bold> Cerebral organ. <bold>(J)</bold> Nephridial tubules. <bold>(K)</bold> Intestine. cg, cephalic glands; co, cerebral organ; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; lv, lateral vessel; mdv, mid-dorsal vessel; nt, nephridial tubule; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; py, pylorus; st, stomach; vcc, ventral cerebral commissure. Scale bars: 15 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, B)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(C, D, F)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(E, H, J, K)</bold>, 25 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G)</bold>, 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(I)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g012.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f13" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;13</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Cerebral glands. <bold>(E)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(F)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(G)</bold> Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(H)</bold> Posterior region of cerebral ganglia. <bold>(I)</bold> Pylorus. <bold>(J)</bold> Ovaries. co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; ov, ovary; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; py, pylorus; rc, rhynchocoel; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, F)</bold>, 25 &#x3bc;m <bold>(B, C)</bold>, 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(D, E)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G&#x2013;I)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(J)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g013.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f14" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;14</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Cerebral glands. <bold>(E)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(F)</bold> Magnification of proboscis musculature. <bold>(G)</bold>  Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(H)</bold> Middle region of cerebral organ <bold>(I)</bold> posterior region of cerebral organ. <bold>(J)</bold> Postcerebral glands of cerebral organ. <bold>(K)</bold> Nephridial tubules. <bold>(L)</bold> Intestine. cg, cephalic glands; co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; nt, nephridial tubule; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; py, pylorus; sg, submuscular glands; st, stomach; stl, stylet; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 15 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, B)</bold>, 60 &#x3bc;m <bold>(C, D, L)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(E)</bold>, 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(F, I, J)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G, H, K)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g014.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f15" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;15</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves. <bold>(E)</bold> Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(F)</bold> Ventral cerebral commissure. <bold>(G)</bold> Cerebral organ. <bold>(H)</bold> Postcerebral glands. <bold>(I)</bold> Pylorus and intestinal caecum. <bold>(J)</bold> Ovaries. cg, cephalic glands; co, cerebral organ; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; nt, nephridial tubule; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; ov, ovaries; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; py, pylorus; st, stomach; sg, submuscular glands; vcc, ventral cerebral commissure. Scale bars: 20 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A, B, H, I)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(C, E, F, J)</bold>, 75 &#x3bc;m <bold>(D)</bold>, 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(G)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g015.tif"/>
</fig>
<fig id="f16" position="float">
<label>Figure&#xa0;16</label>
<caption>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov., transverse sections. <bold>(A)</bold> Body wall in precerebral region. <bold>(B)</bold> Body wall in foregut region. <bold>(C)</bold> Apical organ (arrowhead). <bold>(D)</bold> Cerebral glands. <bold>(E)</bold> Mid-dorsal vessel (arrowhead). <bold>(F)</bold> Proboscis, arrowheads pointing to proboscis nerves, <bold>(G)</bold> Cerebral organ opening. <bold>(H)</bold> Posterior region of cerebral ganglia, arrowhead pointing to vascular plug. <bold>(I)</bold> Nephridial tubules. <bold>(J)</bold> Pylorus, arrowhead pointing to mid-dorsal vessel. <bold>(K)</bold> Intestine. cg, cephalic glands; co, cerebral organ; dcg, dorsal cerebral ganglia; de, dermis; dvm, dorso-ventral muscle in body wall; ep, epidermis; ic, lateral diverticulum of intestinal caecum; ilm, body-wall inner longitudinal muscle; in, intestine; ln, lateral nerve; lv, lateral vessel; nt, nephridial tubule; oc, ocelli; ocm, body-wall outer circular muscle; pcg, postcerebral glands of cerebral organ; pe, proboscis epithelium; pic, proboscis inner circular muscle; pml, proboscis middle longitudinal muscle; pn, proboscis nerve; poc, proboscis outer circular muscle; py, pylorus; vcg, ventral cerebral ganglia. Scale bars: 30 &#x3bc;m <bold>(A)</bold>, 20 &#x3bc;m <bold>(B)</bold>, 50 &#x3bc;m <bold>(C&#x2013;F, G&#x2013;I)</bold>, 150 &#x3bc;m <bold>(J)</bold>, 100 &#x3bc;m <bold>(K)</bold>.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="tiff" xlink:href="fmars-09-906383-g016.tif"/>
</fig>
<p>In the resulting tree (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>), a clade constituted by 59 specimens of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> was sister to another clade formed by the two bathyal species, Cratenemertidae sp. IZ-45644 and Cratenemertea sp. 25DS (possibly pelagic juvenile of Cratenemertidae sp. IZ-45644) and an abyssal species, <italic>Uniporus alisae</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2018</xref>). The <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> clade was divided into three major clades (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). The tree topology reconstructed by the ML analysis was almost identical with the BI tree. Below, we refer to the &#x201c;<italic>N. pulchra&#x2013;Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic>&#x201d; clade as Clade A, the &#x201c;<italic>N. incainca&#x2013;N. punctatula</italic>&#x201d; clade as Clade B, and the &#x201c;<italic>N. lactea&#x2013;N. ganahai</italic>&#x201d; clade as Clade C.</p>
<p>In Clade A, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic> from Sado (the Sea of Japan) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4A, B</bold>
</xref>) was a sister taxon of <italic>N. ogumai</italic> from Araihama (Pacific Ocean); they were nested in a clade along with <italic>N. pulchra</italic>, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105622, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105589 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>), and <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4C, D</bold>
</xref>). <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1 and <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105622 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>) from California constituted a clade supported by 99% of bootstrap value (BS); between the two species, the genetic distances based on COI were 3.4% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S1</bold>
</xref>), smaller than interspecific genetic distances previously reported in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2022</xref>).</p>
<p>Within Clade B, <italic>N. incainca</italic> was first branched from the rest of the members in this clade. <italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov. collected from the Sea of Japan and Kuril Islands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5L&#x2013;P</bold>
</xref>) was sister-related with a clade constituted by &#x201c;<italic>N. bimaculata&#x2013;N. punctatula</italic>&#x201d; clade with full support value. <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. collected from Koganezaki was nested in the &#x201c;<italic>N. bimaculata&#x2013;N. punctatula</italic>&#x201d; clade, together with <italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic> sp. nov. and <italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov.</p>
<p>Clade C was detected for the first time in this study; all members were herein newly included in molecular analyses. In this clade, <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6K, L</bold>
</xref>) was sister to the rest of the members. <italic>Nipponenemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6A&#x2013;G</bold>
</xref>) formed a clade weakly supported by 60% of BS and 0.75 of PP with <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6H&#x2013;J</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6M&#x2013;O</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. ornata</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6P, Q</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6R&#x2013;U</bold>
</xref>), <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6V, W</bold>
</xref>), and Cratenemertidae sp. Guam (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6X</bold>
</xref>) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_2">
<title>Species Delimitation for Clade B</title>
<p>We performed species delimitation analyses using partial sequences of COI (658 bp) to examine putative species boundaries among Clade B. Five distinct lineages (each corresponding to <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>, <italic>N. crypta</italic>, <italic>N. jambio</italic>, <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic>, and <italic>N. punctatula</italic>) were identified by all three methods (TCS, ABGD, and bPTP) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;3</bold>
</xref>). Among them, the maximum value of intraspecific genetic distance was 7.9% of uncorrected <italic>p-</italic>distance (<italic>N. bimaculata</italic>&#x2013;<italic>N. jambio</italic> and <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>&#x2013;<italic>N. punctatula</italic>); the minimum value was 1.6% between <italic>N. crypta</italic> and <italic>N. ojimaorum.</italic>
</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3">
<title>Systematics</title>
<p>Family Cratenemertidae <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">Friedrich, 1968</xref>
</p>
<p>Genus <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall, 1989</xref>
</p>
<p>(= <italic>Collarenemertes</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">Chernyshev, 1993</xref>)</p>
<p>Type species: <italic>Nipponnemertes drepanophoroides</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">Griffin, 1898</xref>.</p>
<p>
<italic>Diagnosis</italic> [given by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">Friedrich (1968)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall (1989)</xref>, and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser (1998)</xref>]: Cratenemertids with generally more than 10 eyes on each side of head in adults. Mouth and rhynchodaeum opening <italic>via</italic> common pore. Anterior cephalic furrows with secondary longitudinal grooves; latter faintly visible or invisible in small individuals. Mid-dorsal cephalic ridge present or absent. Rhynchocoel extending to posterior end of body, consisting of interwoven longitudinal and circular muscle fibres, without lateral pouches. Mid-dorsal vessel penetrating into rhynchocoel to form a single vascular plug. Apical organ and cephalic glands present. Large cerebral organs extending behind brain.</p>
<sec id="s3_3_1">
<title>1 <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic>
</title>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4A, B</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at depths of 8 m by SCUBA diving, Shukunegi, Sado Island, Niigata Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1A</bold>
</xref>), by Naoto Jimi, on 26 September 2019.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: Body 4.5 cm in length, 4.2&#x2013;6.0 mm in width; body uniformly orange coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4A, B</bold>
</xref>). Head conspicuously demarcated from trunk; cephalic patch absent; proboscis pore depressed; mid-dorsal cephalic ridge present but not well developed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4B</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows completely encircling body, meeting at midline on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4B</bold>
</xref>). Ocelli numerous, arranged in lateral margin of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4B</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: In the present study, we refer to the Sado specimen as <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>ogumai</italic> due to morphological similarity in the uniformly orange body. A genetic distances between <italic>N. ogumai</italic> collected from intertidal zone of Araihama, Pacific coast of Japan (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et al., 2015</xref>) is 6.6% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S1</bold>
</xref>), comparable with interspecific COI divergences among hoplonemerteans (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>). Without samples for deposition in museum except the total DNA, we leave a species description to a future study when additional materials for further observation and museum deposition are available.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_2">
<title>2 <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1</title>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4C, D</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: ICHUM 8331, preserved in 99% ethanol; posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at depths of 87&#x2013;89 m by dredging, off Jogashima, Kanagawa Prefecture (35&#xb0;8.42&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;34.74&#x2032;E&#x2013;335&#xb0;8.22&#x2032;N, 139&#xb0;34.67&#x2032;E), by Hiroshi Kajihara, on 19 February 2014.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: Body 1.2 cm in length, 0.8&#x2013;1.2 mm in width; body uniformly pale-orange coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4C, D</bold>
</xref>). Head demarcated from trunk; cephalic patch absent; mid-dorsal cephalic ridge present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4D</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrow completely encircling body, nearly M-shaped on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4D</bold>
</xref>). As many as 19 ocelli irregularly arranged on each side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4D</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: A genetic distance between the present specimen and <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. DNA105622 collected from California at depths of 367&#x2013;389 m (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">Andrade et&#xa0;al., 2012</xref>) is 3.2% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S1</bold>
</xref>); these values fall within previously reported intraspecific COI divergences among hoplonemerteans (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>). Due to the lack of museum deposition, we leave a species description to a future study.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_3">
<title>3 <italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: kakure-omen-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5B&#x2013;D</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>8</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8315, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, bycaught with a gill net from 10 m depth, Sugashima, Mie Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, D</bold>
</xref>), collected by Natsumi Hookabe and Naoto Jimi, on 3 November 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from the type locality, off Sugashima, Mie, Japan, and collected from rock samples bycaught with a gill net. After rock samples were broken into pieces using a hammer, the specimen was found in a rock crack, probably as a result of erosion by rock boring sipunculans, which sympatrically occur around the studied area in Sugashima.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is derived from Greek, <italic>krypt&#xf3;s</italic> (concealed, hidden), referring to cryptic habitat of the new species, among a subtidal rock crack.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 4.2 cm in length, 5 mm in width; body dorsally pale brown and ventrally lighter coloured than dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5B&#x2013;D</bold>
</xref>). Head slightly demarcated from trunk, with a pair of pale brown cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5C, D</bold>
</xref>). Narrow longitudinal midline present between cephalic patches but not reaching to anterior tip of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5C</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrow incompletely encircling body, opening at mid-dorsal line (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5C</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrow V-shaped on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5C</bold>
</xref>). Twenty ocelli in an irregular cluster on each side of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5C</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral ganglia visible through body wall as a pair of red spots (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5C, D</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis 30&#x2013;38 &#x3bc;m thick, with numerous red- and yellow-stained acidophilic cells, blue-stained basophilic cells, and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 39 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8A, B</bold>
</xref>). Body wall musculature with outer circular and inner longitudinal muscle layers (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8A, B</bold>
</xref>); distinct diagonal muscle layers not found. Precerebral septum present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8F</bold>
</xref>). Oesophagus with red-stained acidophilic cells, blue-stained basophilic cells, and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8G, J, K</bold>
</xref>). Dorso-ventral muscles present in cerebral region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8G</bold>
</xref>) and between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8L</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8D</bold>
</xref>) leading to well-developed submuscular glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8A, E</bold>
</xref>). A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral vessels transversely connected above rhynchodaeum at anterior tip of head, running posteriorly in both sides of rhynchodaeum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8E</bold>
</xref>). Mid-dorsal vessel protruding into rhynchocoel to form a single vascular plug in posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8G</bold>
</xref>); mid-dorsal vessel containing red- to orange-coloured blood cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8K</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Proboscis pore opening ventrally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8D</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel muscular wall interwoven with circular and longitudinal musculatures (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8G, J-L</bold>
</xref>). Proboscis epithelium with well-developed papilla (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8H, I</bold>
</xref>). Proboscis musculature composed of outer circular, middle longitudinal, and inner circular muscle layers (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8H, I</bold>
</xref>). Proboscis nerves 13 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8H</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 33.6 &#x3bc;m in length and 22.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth, 72.5 &#x3bc;m in length; stylet-to-basis-length (S/B) ratio 2.16 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 9 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded in body-wall longitudinal muscle layer (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8A, D, E</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs unbranched, extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8F</bold>
</xref>,J) and posteriorly followed by developed gland cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8G</bold>
</xref>). Brain separated from body wall by outer neurilemma; inner neurilemma absent (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;8G, J</bold>
</xref>); dorsal lobe with glomerular structures (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8J</bold>
</xref>). Lateral nerves without accessory nerves and neurochords (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8L</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules anteriorly extending to brain region, forming a bundle of tubules behind brain region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8K</bold>
</xref>). Testes between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f8">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;8L</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: <italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov. is distinguished from all the congeners in the body colouration and cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5C, D</bold>
</xref>). Body colouration of <italic>N. pacifica</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>) described based on preserved specimens is most similar to, but distinguished from <italic>N. crypta</italic> sp. nov. in lacking cephalic patches. The same is true for the Antarctic species <italic>N. variabilis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B56">Korotkevitsch, 1983</xref>); in addition, <italic>N. crypta</italic> sp. nov. differs from <italic>N. variabilis</italic> in the absence of accessory stylet in a central stylet basis (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_4">
<title>4 <italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: jyambio-omen-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5E&#x2013;H</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>Cf. <italic>Cosmocephala japonica</italic>: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B48">Kajihara, 2017</xref>, p. 436, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16F, G</bold>
</xref>.</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8319, preserved in 99% ethanol, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 87&#x2013;89 m depth, off Jogashima, Sagami Bay, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Hiroshi Kajihara, on 19 February 2014. Paratype: ICHUM 8318, preserved in 99% ethanol, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 80 m depth, off Jogashima, Sagami Bay, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Hisanori Kohtsuka, on 25 April 2012.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from the type locality, off Jogashima, Miura (Kanagawa), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 2.0&#x2013;2.2 cm in length, 1.0&#x2013;1.4 mm in width; in trunk region, dorsal body surface uniformly brownish orange; ventral surface slightly lighter coloured than dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5E&#x2013;H</bold>
</xref>). Head with a pair of cephalic patches and a narrow longitudinal midline between cephalic patches on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5E, F</bold>
</xref>); mid-longitudinal line without reaching to anterior end of cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5E, F</bold>
</xref>); ventral surface pale coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5G</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows incompletely encircling body, dorsally discontinuous at midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5F</bold>
</xref>), ventrally extending anteriorly and meeting at midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5G</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrows V-shaped on dorsal side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5H</bold>
</xref>). Eyes 14&#x2013;17 in number, present on each side of lateral margin of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5F, H</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Stylet basis oval, 45.0&#x2013;60.0 &#x3bc;m in length and 35.0&#x2013;48.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth, 95.0&#x2013;120.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.86&#x2013;2.15 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 4&#x2013;5 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: In external morphology, <italic>N. jambio</italic> sp. nov. is extremely similar to <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. However, it is distinguished from the latter in the following features: <italic>i</italic>) trunk region ventrally lighter coloured than dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5G</bold>
</xref>), <italic>ii</italic>) a narrow longitudinal midline (mid-dorsal cephalic ridge) between cephalic patches reaching more anteriorly than <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov., without fusing with cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5F</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Intraspecific COI divergences in this species are 0.0&#x2013;0.3% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S2</bold>
</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_5">
<title>5 <italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[Japanese name: rishiri-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5L&#x2013;P</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>9</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Amphiporus bimaculatus</italic>: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata, 1954</xref>
</p>
<p>
<italic>Collarenemertes bimaculatus</italic>: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">Chernyshev, 1993</xref>
</p>
<p>
<italic>Collarenemertes</italic> cf. <italic>bimaculata</italic>: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>
</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: MIMB 43013, preserved specimen, a proboscis used for DNA extraction, collected by Alexei V. Chernyshev from 5 m depth, among <italic>Modiolus kurilensis</italic>, Vostok Bay, Peter the Great Bay (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1A</bold>
</xref>), Sea of Japan, Russia, 11 August 2015. Paratypes: two specimens, MIMB 43014 and 43015, transverse and sagittal sections of anterior tips, collected by Alexei V. Chernyshev from topotype. Additional specimens: (GenBank specimen ID NipbimIt15), collected by V.G. Kuznetzov from 5&#x2013;15 m depth, Iturup Island, 45&#xb0;22.397&#x2032;N, 148&#xb0;27.296&#x2032;E, Sea of Okhotsk (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1A</bold>
</xref>), 19 August 2019; 16 specimens from Sea of Japan and Kuril Islands (Zoological Museum of Far East Federal University and personal collection of AVC).</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is known from the type locality (Vostok Bay) and Kuril Islands (Iturup Island). Externally identical specimens were collected in Posyet, Ussuri, and Vladimir Bays, Valentin Bight (Sea of Japan), Aniwa Bay (South Sakhalin), Shikotan Island (Kuril Island), and Rausu, Hokkaido (Sea of Okhotsk) (Hookabe &amp; Jimi, personal observation) from the intertidal to a depth of 14 m. As well, the species was reported from Rishiri Island, Hokkkaido (Sea of Japan) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata, 1954</xref>). The present species is extracted from substrate samples, in which sedentary mytilids <italic>(Modiolus kurilensis</italic> and <italic>Crenomytilus grayanus</italic>) and calcareous algae (<italic>Bossiella</italic> sp.) were included.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is a noun in the genitive case, after Dr. Neonila Polyakova, to whom we acknowledge her significant contribution to molecular systematics of nemerteans.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 5&#x2013;16 cm in length (12 cm in holotype), 5&#x2013;6 mm in width (up to 12&#x2013;15 mm in contracted specimens); body dorsally brownish-red or brick-red and ventrally beige or whitish (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5L</bold>
</xref>). Head triangular from above, with a pair of darker triangular cephalic patches and a longitudinal midline between cephalic patches on dorsal surface; mid-longitudinal line not reaching to anterior tip of head and not fused with cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5M, N</bold>
</xref>). Narrow longitudinal midline between cephalic patches not reaching to anterior tip of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5M, N, P</bold>
</xref>). When contracted, head can be retracted into body, forming a collar (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9D</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrow incompletely encircling body, opening at mid-dorsal line, with secondary grooves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5O</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic groove V-shaped on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5M</bold>
</xref>). Eyes 12&#x2013;23 in number, present on each side of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5P</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous ciliated and orange-stained glandular cells. Dermis up to 60&#x2013;80 &#x3bc;m thick in contracted specimens. Body-wall musculature as in other species in the genus, diagonal muscles detected by confocal laser scanning microscopy (<italic>Chernyshev, 2010</italic>: <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;3</bold>
</xref>). Pylorus sporadically with glandular cells; intestinal caecum anteriorly extending beneath pylorus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5P</bold>
</xref>), with 5&#x2013;6 pairs of lateral pouches. Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9F</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9B</bold>
</xref>) and the subsequent submuscular glands as in other species in the genus. Precerebral vessel extending above rhynchodaeum at anterior tip of head and posteriorly bifurcated (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9A</bold>
</xref>). Mid-dorsal vessel protruding into rhynchocoel to form a single vascular plug in posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;9D, E</bold>
</xref>); blood cells colourless.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore sub-terminal, opening ventrally. Rhynchocoel musculature consisting of interwoven longitudinal and circular muscle fibres (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;9E, F</bold>
</xref>). Proboscis nerves 16&#x2013;17 in number. Stylet basis oval, 118&#x2013;156 (156 in holotype) &#x3bc;m in length and 80&#x2013;97 (94 in holotype) &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth,152&#x2013;222 (218 in holotype) &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.14&#x2013;1.67 (1.39 in holotype) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two (rarely four or five) accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 3&#x2013;10 (7 in holotype) stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded in body-wall muscle layer (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9A</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs extending to posterior region of brain, posteriorly bifurcated (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9C</bold>
</xref>); posterior glandular part located between lateral blood vessel and lateral nerve (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;9E</bold>
</xref>). Brain and lateral nerves as in other species of the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules branching near lateral blood vessels. Gonads, gonoducts, and gonopores not found in the material examined.</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: In external morphology, <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov. is very similar to <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>. However, it is distinguishable from the latter by the presence of a narrow longitudinal midline (mid-dorsal cephalic ridge) between cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5M, N, P</bold>
</xref>). In the original description of <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe (1901)</xref> wrote that the head had two oval, black or very dark brown patches in material from Victoria (British Columbia, Canada), Sitka (Alaska, USA), and Puget Sound (Washington, USA). Later, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905</xref>: pl. 2, figure 21) illustrated a specimen with two narrow triangular cephalic patches. Photographs of the similar specimens are provided in BOLD (<uri xlink:href="http://v3.boldsystems.org/index.php/Taxbrowser_Taxonpage?taxid=939114">http://v3.boldsystems.org/index.php/Taxbrowser_Taxonpage?taxid=939114</uri>). Dr. Frank Crandall (personal communication) regarded that specimens of <italic>N. bimaculata</italic> with oval and triangular cephalic patches belong to two different species. If this is the case, specimens with oval head spots should be assigned to <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>. <italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov. is distinguished from <italic>N. bimaculata</italic> in the Northeast Pacific in having triangular patches by wider and darker cephalic patches.</p>
<p>From Japanese waters, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata (1954)</xref> reported a similar form with the present species from sublittoral among laminarian holdfasts, Rishiri Island (Hokkaido), the Sea of Japan. As noted in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B25">Crandall et&#xa0;al. (2002)</xref>, the form differs from <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe&#x2019;s (1901)</xref> description of <italic>N. bimaculata</italic> in having triangular cephalic patches, and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B25">Crandall et&#xa0;al. (2002)</xref> noted that the form identified by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata (1954)</xref> differs from <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe&#x2019;s (1901)</xref> taxon in having a pair of quadrangular head markings, and rather resembles <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov. Therefore, we herein redescribe <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata&#x2019;s (1954)</xref> taxon as <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_6">
<title>6 <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: benishouga-omen-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5I&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>10</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8324, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by SCUBA diving from 12 m depth, Koganezaki, Shizuoka Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A,C</bold>
</xref>), by Masanori Okanishi, on 21 October 2020. Paratypes: ICHUM 8325, fixed in Bouin&#x2019;s fluid and later preserved in 70% ethanol, collected by SCUBA diving from 8 m depth, Koganezaki, Shizuoka Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 6 January 2021; ICHUM 8326, fixed in Bouin&#x2019;s fluid and later preserved in 70% ethanol, collected by SCUBA diving from 7 m depth, Koganezaki, Shizuoka Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Naoto Jimi, on 6 January 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species has been currently known only from Koganezaki (Shizuoka), Japan, inhabiting subtidally under rocks on sandy substrates (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1E</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is a noun in the genitive plural, named after Tomohito Ojima and Masako Ojima, who organized a field survey on subtidal invertebrate fauna in Koganezaki; all the specimens of the new species were collected during the survey.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 2.2 cm in length, 1.2 mm in width; in trunk region, dorsal body surface uniformly bright red coloured; ventral surface the same colour as dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5I&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>). Head with a pair of cephalic patches on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>); ventral surface pale coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5K</bold>
</xref>). Narrow longitudinal midline between cephalic patches not reaching to anterior tip of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows incompletely encircling body, dorsally discontinuous at midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>), ventrally extending anteriorly and meeting at midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5K</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrows V-shaped on dorsal side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>). Eyes arranged on each side of lateral margin (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>); number of eyes not counted for the present species.</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-stained acidophilic cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;10A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 30 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface in precerebral region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10A</bold>
</xref>); in foregut region more flattened and without forming conspicuous cup-like structure (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;10A, B</bold>
</xref>), esophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10G</bold>
</xref>), pylorus, intestinal caecum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;10H, K</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Dorso-ventral muscles present in cerebral region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10J</bold>
</xref>) and in intestinal region between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10L</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands and the subsequent submuscular glands as in other species in the genus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10A</bold>
</xref>). A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral vessels transversely connected above rhynchodaeum at anterior tip of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10E</bold>
</xref>). A single vascular plug present in posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10G</bold>
</xref>); mid-dorsal vessel not well distinguished thorough histology in the present species.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore positioned sub-terminally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5K</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10G</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10H</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;10H, I</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 13 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10H</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 53.0 &#x3bc;m in length and 32.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth, 98.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.85 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 7&#x2013;8 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded in body-wall muscle layer (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10A</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs unbranched (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;9F, J</bold>
</xref>) and followed by glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10G</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Lateral nerves lacking accessory nerves and neurochords (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;10K, L</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules forming a bundle of tubules behind brain region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f10">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;10K</bold>
</xref>). Gonads, gonoducts, and gonopores not found in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: <italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. is similar to <italic>N. arenaria</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5A</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>, <italic>N. crypta</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5B&#x2013;D</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. jambio</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5E&#x2013;H</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5L&#x2013;P</bold>
</xref>), and <italic>N. punctatula</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5Q&#x2013;T</bold>
</xref>) because these species possess cephalic patches in common. However, <italic>N</italic>. <italic>ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. can be differentiated from these species by the colouration of the dorsal and ventral body surfaces, which is the same in <italic>N</italic>. <italic>ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5I&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>), whereas the dorsal surface is darker than the ventral in other species. In terms of the colour contrast between the dorsal and ventral body surfaces, <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. most closely resembles <italic>N. jambio</italic> sp. nov. because the ventral surface in the latter is only slightly lighter than the dorsal surface; in other species (<italic>N. arenaria</italic>, <italic>N. bimaculata</italic>, <italic>N. crypta</italic> sp. nov., <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov., and <italic>N. punctatula</italic>), the contrast is more prominent with a darker dorsal surface against paler ventral one. Still, <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov. is distinguishable from <italic>N. jambio</italic> sp. nov. by the mid-dorsal cephalic line, which is <italic>i</italic>) not reaching to the anterior end of the cephalic patches, <italic>ii</italic>) laterally fusing to the cephalic patches, and <italic>iii</italic>) posteriorly fusing to the dorsal dark colour (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5J</bold>
</xref>); in <italic>N. jambio</italic> sp. nov., the mid-dorsal cephalic line <italic>i</italic>) extends anteriorly almost reaching to the level of the anterior end of the cephalic patches, <italic>ii</italic>) is laterally separated from the cephalic patches, and <italic>iii</italic>) is not continuous with the dorsal dark colour (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5F</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Cosmocephala japonica</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B77">Stimpson, 1857</xref>&#x2014;currently <italic>Amphiporus japonica</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B77">Stimpson, 1857</xref>)&#x2014;is anticipated to be a species in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B48">Kajihara, 2017</xref>); it was originally described based on specimens intertidally collected from Shimoda (Shizuoka), geographically close to Koganezaki, the type locality of <italic>N. ojimaorum.</italic> sp. nov. However, by having ventrally pale-coloured body surface, <italic>Cosmocephala japonica</italic> is distinguished from <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_7">
<title>7 <italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)</title>
<p>[Japanese name: madara-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5Q&#x2013;T</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: ICHUM 8328, preserved in formalin, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at intertidal, Tateyama, Mie Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Ryuta Yoshida, on 13 June 2018. ICHUM 8329, preserved in formalin, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at intertidal, Sugashima, Mie Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, D</bold>
</xref>), by Naoto Jimi, on 24 June 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is widely known from Japanese coastal waters from Hokkaido to Nagasaki.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 4.0&#x2013;5.2 cm in length, 8&#x2013;12 mm in width; in trunk region, dorsal body surface with a dorsal brown blotch pattern (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5Q, R</bold>
</xref>) or uniformly brownish (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5S, T</bold>
</xref>); ventral surface pale-coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5T</bold>
</xref>). Head with a pair of cephalic patches and a narrow longitudinal midline between cephalic patches on dorsal surface; mid-longitudinal line without reaching to anterior end of cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5Q&#x2013;T</bold>
</xref>)). Posterior cephalic furrows V-shaped on dorsal side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5Q</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: Body colouration pattern of the present species varies from previously known brown blotch pattern (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5Q, R</bold>
</xref>) to uniformly brown colour without blotched (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5S, T</bold>
</xref>). Intraspecific COI divergences in this species are 0.0&#x2013;0.2% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S2</bold>
</xref>), suggesting intraspecific variation of body colouration pattern in <italic>N. punctatula.</italic>
</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_8">
<title>8 <italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese ganaha-omen-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6A&#x2013;G</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>11</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>?<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89">Yamaoka, 2005</xref>, p. 151&#x2013;152.</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8317, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 116&#x2013;211 m depth, off Jogashima, Miura, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, D</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 31 July 2020. Paratypes: ICHUM 8316, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 71.2&#x2013;79.2 m depth, off Noto, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, B</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 20 November 2019.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species has been collected off Jogashima (Kanagawa Prefecture), Noto (Ishikawa Prefecture), Ofunato (Iwate Prefecture), and Tosa (Kochi Prefecture), Japan, likely preferring muddy to sandy sediments (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1F, G</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is a noun in the genitive case, after Ikumasa Ganaha, to whom we acknowledge his significant contribution to molecular experiments including DNA extraction, PCR amplification, sequencing, and organizing the obtained molecular data for several specimens used in the present study.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 1.2&#x2013;1.6 cm in length, 1.5&#x2013;2.0 mm in width; body uniformly pale pink to yellow coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6A&#x2013;E</bold>
</xref>). Head not conspicuously demarcated from trunk; cephalic patch absent (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6A&#x2013;D</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows completely encircling body, extending anteriorly and meeting at midline on ventral side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6F</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrows V-shaped on dorsal surface, completely encircling body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6B</bold>
</xref>). As many as 15&#x2013;21 ocelli irregularly arranged on each side, varying in sizes; 2 to 3 ocelli fused in several specimens (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6C, F, G</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-, yellow-, and blue-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 25 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11A, B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11A, B</bold>
</xref>), oesophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11H, I</bold>
</xref>), pylorus, and intestinal caecum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11F</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11K</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11C</bold>
</xref>) leading to well-developed submuscular glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11A, D</bold>
</xref>). A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral vessels transversely connected above rhynchodaeum at anterior tip of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11D</bold>
</xref>). Mid-dorsal vessel present between rhynchocoel and pylorus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11F</bold>
</xref>); vascular plug not detected in the present species.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore sub-terminal, opening ventrally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6F</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel musculature, proboscis epithelium, and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11F, G</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11F</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 57.0&#x2013;71.0 &#x3bc;m in length 45.0&#x2013;47.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet vertically sculptured, 89.0&#x2013;92.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.29&#x2013;1.56 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing four stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded sub-dermally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11A, C, D</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs ventrolaterally opening in precerebral region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11E</bold>
</xref>) and extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11H, I</bold>
</xref>), followed by glandular cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11J</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11H&#x2013;J</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;11F, K</bold>
</xref>) as in other species of the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules branching near lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11F</bold>
</xref>). Ovaries between intestinal diverticula; each ovary containing 10 or more oocytes; oocytes 100&#x2013;150 &#x3bc;m in diameter (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11K</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: <italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> resembles <italic>N. africana</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86">Wheeler, 1940</xref>), <italic>N. danae</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">Friedrich, 1957</xref>) (probably synonym of <italic>N. pulchra</italic> in morphological basis; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg, 1985</xref>), <italic>N. magna</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B71">Punnett, 1903</xref>), <italic>N. pulchra</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">Johnston, 1837</xref>), and <italic>N. sanguinea</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser, 1998</xref> in having pale pink to yellow body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6A&#x2013;E</bold>
</xref>) and intestinal caecum extending to pyloric region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f11">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;11F</bold>
</xref>) and anteriorly extending in posterior region of esophagus. However, it is distinguished from <italic>N. pulchra</italic> (also probably from <italic>N. danae</italic>) in lacking an accessory stylet in the basis of the central stylet armature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Between the remaining three species, the number of the proboscis nerves can be useful for species distinction; it is 10 in <italic>N. ganahai</italic> sp. nov., 20 in <italic>N. magna</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B71">Punnett, 1903</xref>), and 12 in <italic>N. sanguinea</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser, 1998</xref>). Furthermore, <italic>N. sanguinea</italic> is distinguished from <italic>N. ganahai</italic> in the red-coloured fluid contained in blood vessels due to red blood corpuscles (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser, 1998</xref>); red blood was not visible in a live squeezed specimen of <italic>N. ganahai</italic> sp. nov. through a light microscope (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6G</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Intraspecific COI divergences in this species are 0.0&#x2013;0.8% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S3</bold>
</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_9">
<title>9 <italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: koza-sujinashi-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6H&#x2013;J</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>12</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>?<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89">Yamaoka, 2005</xref>, p. 152&#x2013;153.</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8320, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, posterior tip used for DNA extraction, found during anaesthetization for ascidians in menthol-floated seawater; the ascidians were collected by Naohiro Hasegawa from 12 m depth by SCUBA diving, Kaminoshima, Koza, Wakayama Prefecture (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;1A</bold>
</xref>), Japan, on 11 May 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The present specimen was found among rocky substrate samples. In the substrate samples, several sessile invertebrates such as sponges, ascidians, and bryozoans were colonized. Currently known from the type locality, Koza (Wakayama Prefecture), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is derived from the type locality, Koza, Wakayama Prefecture, Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 1.5 cm in length, 1.0 mm in width; background generally pale-coloured, mottled with red-brown and white dots; red-brown dots more densely distributed in dorso-anterior region of body; white dots uniformly distributed on both dorsal and ventral surfaces (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6H&#x2013;J</bold>
</xref>). Head devoid of red-brown pigments and slightly demarcated from body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6I</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows not conspicuous, probably discontinuous on dorsal midline, but ventrally meeting at midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6I, J</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrows completely encircling body and V-shaped on dorsal side (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6I, J</bold>
</xref>). As many as 14 eyes arranged in two irregular rows at lateral margin on each side of head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6I</bold>
</xref>). Internal organs visible through body wall; proboscis pure white, extending three-fourths the body; foregut and intestine yellow coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6H</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-, yellow-, blue-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis thin, up to 20 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12A, B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12A, B</bold>
</xref>), oesophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12I</bold>
</xref>), pylorus, and intestinal caecum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12E</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Intestinal caecum anteriorly extending beneath pylorus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12E</bold>
</xref>). Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12K</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12D</bold>
</xref>) followed by subsequent submuscular glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12H</bold>
</xref>). A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral vessels as in other species in the genus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12D</bold>
</xref>). Mid-dorsal vessel passing above pylorus and containing red to orange blood cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12E</bold>
</xref>); vascular plug indistinguishable in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore sub-terminal, opening ventrally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6J</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12E, J</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12E, F, J</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12E&#x2013;G, J</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12F</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 49.6 &#x3bc;m in length and 32.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet vertically sculptured, 75.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.51 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 8 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup- ocelli embedded sub-dermally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12A, H</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12I</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12I</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;12E, J, K</bold>
</xref>) as in other species of the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules branching near lateral blood vessels, latter containing red to orange blood cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12J</bold>
</xref>). Gonads, gonoducts, and gonopores not found in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: Currently five species have been known to possess pale coloured body mottled with red to brown dots in the genus: <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>), <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer, 1965</xref>), <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., <italic>N. ornata</italic> sp. nov., and <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6</bold>
</xref>). <italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. is distinguished from the two previously known species, <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> and <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic>, by having submuscular glands originated from cephalic glands, although it could not be traced because of poor fixation or staining in <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> and <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> and its validity as a diagnostic character needs to be reexamined in future study. In addition, <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. differs from <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> in having 10 proboscis nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f12">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;12F</bold>
</xref>) and 8 accessory stylets in each pouch (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>), whereas <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> possesses 9 proboscis nerves and 2&#x2013;3 accessory stylets per pouch (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer, 1965</xref>). No information as to the proboscis in <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> is available, because the proboscis was lost in the type material (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>). According to the original description, one of the notable anatomical features found in <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> is the complex alimentary canal with oesophageal and cardiac caeca (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>, pl. XX, fig. 121). In the species herein described, including <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., complex alimental canals as depicted by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref> were not observed. This would also allow the distinction of <italic>N. occidentalis</italic> from <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov.</p>
<p>In contrast to <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> and <italic>N. occidentalis</italic>, no conspicuous difference is found in the internal morphology between <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov., <italic>N. ornata</italic> sp. nov., and <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. <italic>Nipponemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov. differs from <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. in the lower density of brown dots on the body surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6P, Q</bold>
</xref>). Although the species distinction is molecularly supported by the resulting phylogenetic tree, where the two species were not in a sister relation (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>), further observation based on additional materials is required to examine if any subtle differences in the spotting pattern might represent interspecific variation and thus could be used for species discrimination. A brown colour pattern similar to the one found in <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> is also present in <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> but the pattern is irregular in the latter specie (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6R</bold>
</xref>) rather than the uniformly distributed dots in <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6H</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>In the resulting molecular phylogenetic tree (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>), <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> formed a clade with <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> with high support values. Although we could not obtain COI sequences for them even with specific primers for their delimitation, the nucleotide differences between the two species were comparable with interspecific divergences observed in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_10">
<title>10 <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: irojiro-sujinashi-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6K, L</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>13</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>?<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89">Yamaoka, 2005</xref>, p. 151&#x2013;152</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8321, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at depths of 98&#x2013;120 m by dredging, Takase, off Shimoda, Shizuoka Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 25 March 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from the type locality, off Shimoda (Shizuoka), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is derived from the Latin <italic>lacteus</italic>, meaning &#x201c;milky&#x201d;, after the uniformly pale body colouration in this species.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 0.7 cm in length, 0.8 mm in width; body uniformly pale; intestinal region pale-orange due to internal organs (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6K</bold>
</xref>). Head demarcated from trunk and without cephalic patches. Anterior cephalic furrows completely encircling body. Posterior cephalic furrows V-shaped on dorsal surface, completely encircling body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6K</bold>
</xref>). As many as 12 eyes arranged on each side of lateral margin (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6L</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 25 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface in precerebral region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13A</bold>
</xref>); in foregut to intestine regions, dermis becoming thicker and more flattened without forming cup-like structure (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13A, B</bold>
</xref>); oesophagus, pylorus, and intestinal caecum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13I</bold>
</xref>) as in other species of the genus. Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13I</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13D</bold>
</xref>) leading to well-developed submuscular glands. A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral vessels, mid-dorsal vessel, and vascular plug difficult to be confirmed in type material.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore opening ventrally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6L</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13G&#x2013;I</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13E</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13F</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13E</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 72.0 &#x3bc;m in length and 40.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth, 90.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.25 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 7 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded sub-dermally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13A</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs unbranched, extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13G, H</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13G, H</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;13I, J</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules difficult to be confirmed in type material. Ovaries between intestinal lateral diverticula; each ovary containing 20 or more oocytes; oocytes 42 &#x3bc;m in diameter (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13J</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov. resembles <italic>N. africana</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86">Wheeler, 1940</xref>), <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. (present study), and <italic>N. variabilis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B56">Korotkevitsch, 1983</xref>) in having uniformly pale coloured body, posterior cephalic furrows completely encircling body, and the circulatory system lacking red blood corpuscles. <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov. is characterized by the ocelli arranged in a single row at lateral margin of the head (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6L</bold>
</xref>). As depicted in the original illustration based on a preserved specimen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86">Wheeler, 1940</xref>: <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f9">
<bold>Figures 9B, C</bold>
</xref>), the ocelli in <italic>N. africana</italic> are arranged irregularly, and the similar arrangement is found in <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6N</bold>
</xref>). <italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov. differs from <italic>N. variabilis</italic> in the absence of accessory stylet in the central stylet basis (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Nipponnemertes schollaerti</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler, 1934</xref>), for which no information on posterior cephalic furrows is available from <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler (1934)</xref>&#x2019;s original description, is distinguished from <italic>N. lactea</italic> sp. nov. in the larger numbers of the ocelli on each side of head&#x2014;55 in <italic>N. schollaerti</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg, 1985</xref>) <italic>vs</italic> 12 in <italic>N. lactea</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6L</bold>
</xref>)&#x2014;and more than ten times larger body size&#x2014;97 mm in <italic>N. schollaerti</italic> (preserved, mature male) <italic>vs</italic> 7 mm in <italic>N. lactea</italic> (living, mature female).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_11">
<title>11 <italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: noto-sujinashi-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6M&#x2013;O</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>14</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8322, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 70&#x2013;91 m depth, off Noto, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, B</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 20 November 2019. Paratype: ICHUM 8323, fixed in 10% formalin and later preserved in 70% ethanol, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected by dredging from 70&#x2013;91 m depth, off Noto, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, B</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 20 November 2019.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species has been only known from the type locality, off Noto (Ishikawa Prefecture), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is derived from the type locality, Noto, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 1.2 cm in length, 1.2 mm in width; body uniformly pale to pale-yellow coloured (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6M</bold>
</xref>). Head not demarcated from trunk, mottled with white spots along dorsal midline (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6N, O</bold>
</xref>); cephalic patch absent (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5N, O</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows not well developed. Posterior cephalic furrow V-shaped on dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6M</bold>
</xref>), completely encircling body. As many as 19&#x2013;20 reddish brown ocelli irregularly arranged on each side; each ocelli irregular in size and shape; 2 to 3 ocelli fusing with each other (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6N</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-, orange-, and blue-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 21 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface in both precerebral (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14A</bold>
</xref>) and foregut regions (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature as in other species in the genus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14A, B</bold>
</xref>). Oesophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14G</bold>
</xref>) and pylorus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14K</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14L</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14D</bold>
</xref>) and submuscular glands present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f13">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;13G</bold>
</xref>). A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral and mid-dorsal vessel not observed.</p>
<p>Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14G&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14E</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14E, F</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14E</bold>
</xref>). Stylet armature not observed in the specimen examined. Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing more than two stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14E</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded in body-wall longitudinal muscle layer (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14D</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14G&#x2013;I</bold>
</xref>), followed by glandular cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14J</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14H, I</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;14K,L</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules branching near lateral blood vessel (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14K</bold>
</xref>). Gonads and gonoducts not found in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: Among 19 species previously described and 13 species herein reported, <italic>N. sanguinea</italic> and <italic>N. schollaerti</italic> are most similar to <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. due to the uniformly pale-coloured body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6M</bold>
</xref>) and the irregular arrangement of ocelli (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6N, O</bold>
</xref>) (see the Remarks section of <italic>N. lactea</italic> sp. nov.). However, <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. can be differentiated from the two species in the number of proboscis nerves: 10 in <italic>N. notoensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f14">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;14E</bold>
</xref>) <italic>vs</italic> 11 in <italic>N. sanguinea vs</italic> 14 in <italic>N. schollaerti</italic>.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_12">
<title>12 <italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese name: kazari-sujinashi-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6P, Q</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>15</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>?<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 1: <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B89">Yamaoka, 2005</xref>, p. 152&#x2013;153.</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8327, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at depths of 70&#x2013;91 m by dredging, off Noto, Ishikawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, B</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 20 November 2019.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from the type locality, off Noto (Ishikawa Prefecture), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is a feminine form of Latin <italic>ornatus</italic>, meaning &#x201c;adorned or decorated&#x201d;, derived from the body coloration mottled with white and brown dots in the present species.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 1.8 cm in length, 0.9 mm in width; background uniformly pale coloured, mottled with white and brown dots; white dots conspicuous in dorsal surface of head region; brown dots more densely distributed in dorso-anterior region of body than ventral and posterior region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6P</bold>
</xref>). Head not well demarcated from trunk; cephalic patch absent (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6Q</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows not well developed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6Q</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic groove V-shaped on dorsal surface, completely encircling body (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6Q</bold>
</xref>). Ocelli 16 or 17 in number, not regularly arranged in rows, varying in size (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6Q</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red-and yellow-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis thin, up to 20 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface in precerebral (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15A</bold>
</xref>) and foregut regions (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15A, B</bold>
</xref>) and oesophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15E, F</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Intestinal caecum anteriorly extending beneath pylorus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15I</bold>
</xref>). Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15J</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15A</bold>
</xref>) and the subsequent submuscular glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15E</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15C</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral and mid-dorsal vessel not well observed in our histological sections.</p>
<p>Proboscis pore opening ventrally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6P</bold>
</xref>). Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15F, I</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15D</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15D</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15D</bold>
</xref>). Stylet not observed in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded sub-dermally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15E</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15E&#x2013;G</bold>
</xref>), followed by glandular cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15H</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15F, G</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;15I, J</bold>
</xref>) as in other species of the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules not observed in the present specimen. Ovaries developing between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f15">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;15J</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: The present species is extremely similar to <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov. in having white and brown dots on uniformly pale body; however, it can be differentiated from the latter in brown dots more densely scattering on body surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6H</bold>
</xref>) (see also the Remarks section of <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> sp. nov.). Internal morphology of the two species is not remarkably different, although there might be other useful characters which are not obtained for <italic>N. ornata</italic> sp. nov. in this study (e.g., number of accessory stylets in proboscis).</p>
<p>Our molecular phylogenetic tree shows that <italic>N. ornata</italic> is sister-related with <italic>N. notoensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). <italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> differs from <italic>N. ornata</italic> in lacking dotted pattern (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6M</bold>
</xref>). Moreover, uncorrected <italic>p-</italic>distance between the two species was 9%, higher than the threshold value (5%) used for species separation in nemertean systematics (e.g., <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_13">
<title>13 <italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. Hookabe, Kajihara &amp; Chernyshev</title>
<p>[New Japanese Sugashima-sujinashi-himomushi]</p>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6R&#x2013;U</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>16</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8330, serial transverse sections of anterior tip to intestine, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, bycaught with a gill net from 10 m depth, Sugashima, Mie Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A,D</bold>
</xref>), collected by Natsumi Hookabe and Naoto Jimi, on 3 November 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from the type locality. Worms were picked up from rocky substrate samples bycaught with a gill net.</p>
<p>
<italic>Etymology</italic>: The specific name is derived from the type locality, Sugashima (Mie Prefecture), Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 0.9 cm in length, 1.1 mm in width; background uniformly pale coloured, with irregular, leopard-like brown mottling (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6R</bold>
</xref>); mottling pattern ventrally faded. Head not well demarcated from trunk; cephalic patch lacking (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6S</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows not well developed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6S</bold>
</xref>). Posterior cephalic furrows not found in the specimen examined. 12 or 13 ocelli irregularly arranged (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6T</bold>
</xref>). Proboscis white in colour when everted.</p>
<p>
<italic>Internal morphology.</italic> Epidermis with numerous red- and yellow-stained cells and ciliated cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16A, B</bold>
</xref>). Dermis up to 24 &#x3bc;m thick, forming cup-like structures on distal surface in precerebral (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16A</bold>
</xref>) and foregut regions (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16B</bold>
</xref>). Body-wall musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16A, B</bold>
</xref>), oesophagus (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16E, H</bold>
</xref>), pylorus, and intestinal caecum (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16J</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Dorso-ventral muscles present between intestinal diverticula (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16K</bold>
</xref>). Cephalic glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16D</bold>
</xref>) and the subsequent submuscular glands as in other species in the genus. A single apical organ present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16C</bold>
</xref>). Mid-dorsal vessel (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16E, J</bold>
</xref>) protruding into rhynchocoel to form a single vascular plug in posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16H</bold>
</xref>); mid-dorsal vessel (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16E, J</bold>
</xref>) as well as lateral vessels (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16I, J</bold>
</xref>) containing red to orange coloured blood cells.</p>
<p>Rhynchocoel musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16E, H, J, K</bold>
</xref>), proboscis epithelium (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16F</bold>
</xref>), and proboscis musculature (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16F</bold>
</xref>) as in other species in the genus. Proboscis nerves 10 in number (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16F</bold>
</xref>). Stylet basis oval, 75.0 &#x3bc;m in length and 48.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet vertically sculptured, 115.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.38 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing 7 stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Pigment-cup ocelli embedded sub-dermally (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16I</bold>
</xref>). Cerebral organs extending to posterior region of brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16G&#x2013;I</bold>
</xref>), followed by glandular cells (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16I</bold>
</xref>). Brain (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16H</bold>
</xref>) and lateral nerves (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;16I, J</bold>
</xref>) as in other species of the genus.</p>
<p>Nephridial tubules branching near lateral blood vessels (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16K</bold>
</xref>). Gonads, gonoducts, and gonopores not found in the specimen examined.</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: Apart from <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov., irregular brown mottling on uniformly pale body is known in <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> (see the Remarks section of <italic>N. ornata</italic> sp. nov.). However, <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. is discriminated from <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> by having submuscular glands (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f16">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;16A</bold>
</xref>) and the larger number of accessory stylets per pouch: 7 in <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov. (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6T</bold>
</xref>) and 2&#x2013;3 in <italic>N. madagascarensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer, 1965</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s3_3_14">
<title>14 <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. 2</title>
<p>(<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;6V, W</bold>
</xref>, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>7</bold>
</xref>)</p>
<p>
<italic>Material examined</italic>: Holotype: ICHUM 8332, preserved in 70% ethanol, a posterior tip used for DNA extraction, collected at depths of 116&#x2013;211 m by dredging, off Jogashima, Miura, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;1A, C</bold>
</xref>), by Natsumi Hookabe, on 30 July 2021.</p>
<p>
<italic>Habitat and geographic distribution</italic>: The species is only known from Jogashima, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan.</p>
<p>
<italic>Description</italic>: <italic>External features.</italic> Body 0.9 cm in length, 0.8 mm in width; body uniformly pale; intestinal region visible through body wall as pinkish (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6V</bold>
</xref>). Head not demarcated from trunk, without cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6V</bold>
</xref>). Anterior cephalic furrows not well developed. Posterior cephalic furrow not visible. As many as 13 ocelli present (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6W</bold>
</xref>). Precerebral and lateral vessels filled with red corpuscles (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6W</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>Proboscis pore sub-terminal. Stylet basis oval, 76.0 &#x3bc;m in length and 42.0 &#x3bc;m in maximum width; central stylet smooth, 96.0 &#x3bc;m in length; S/B ratio 1.38 (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Two accessory stylet pouches present, each containing six stylets (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>).</p>
<p>
<italic>Remarks</italic>: The species is characterized by pinkish intestine visible through body wall (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6V</bold>
</xref>). Due to the absence of morphological voucher specimen, we leave the species as an unidentified form in the present study.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="s4" sec-type="discussion">
<title>Discussion</title>
<sec id="s4_1">
<title>Molecular Systematics of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>
</title>
<p>In this study, species diversity of <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> in Japanese and the Far Eastern Russian waters was significantly updated from 4 to 14 species, in which newly discovered 9 species as well as herein redescribed <italic>N. bimaculata</italic> sensu <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">Iwata (1954)</xref> (= <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov.) are included (<xref ref-type="table" rid="T4">
<bold>Table&#xa0;4</bold>
</xref>). Our molecular phylogenetic analyses recovered three major lineages in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). In a previous study based on six congeners (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>), two well-supported clades each corresponding to Clade A and Clade B (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>) have been detected. With increased taxon sampling especially in subtidal to deep-sea species, Clade C was newly confirmed in the present study.</p>
<table-wrap id="T4" position="float">
<label>Table&#xa0;4</label>
<caption>
<p>An updated species list in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> and <italic>Cratenemertes amboiensis</italic> with selected morphological characters and ecological information.</p>
</caption>
<table frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="left">Species</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Type locality</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Distribution</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Depth</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Habitat</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">External Colouration</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Cephalic patches</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Mid-dorsal cephalic ridge</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Numbers of proboscis nerves</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Cerebral organs</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">References</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes</italic>
<break/>
<italic>africana</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86">Wheeler, 1940</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Shelly Beach (South Africa)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Algoa Bay, Shelly Beach, Saldanha Bay (South Africa)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among algae <italic>Hypnea specifica</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Colour white, pink, pinkish yellow or buff, becoming lighter anteriorly and deeper posteriorly</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">11</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B86">Wheeler (1940)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B67">McDermott (1997)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes arenaria</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B83">Ushakov, 1927</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Ussuri Bay (Russia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Peter the Great Bay (Russia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">15&#x2013;62 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Subtidally on sandy bottom</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally brown with white mottling (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4A</bold>
</xref>); lateral and ventral margin paler</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">14&#x2013;15</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B83">Ushakov (1927)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">Chernyshev (1993)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes bimaculata</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe, 1901</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from Victoria, British Colombia (Canada) and Puget Sound (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pacific coasts of North America; specimens identified as this species reported from eastern Russia and Japan likely to be <italic>N. neonilae</italic> sp. nov.; as far south as Ensenada in Mexico but the species identity uncertain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to subtidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to sublittoral, among laminarian holdfasts, in rock crevices, beneath stones or among algae, hydroids, mussels and other growths on rocks and pier pilings</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally deep brownish orange and ventrally uniformly pale</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present; narrow triangular</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">16</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Large cerebral organs extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">Coe (1901)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">Gibson &amp; Crandall (1989)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes crypta</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">10 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">In rock cracks probably resulting from rock boring sipunculans</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally pale brown and ventrally lighter coloured without mottling (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4B&#x2013;D</bold>
</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">13</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes danae</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">Friedrich, 1957</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Faroe Island (Denmark)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Faroe Island (Denmark); Arctic waters</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally reddish and ventrally whitish; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref> indicated morphological similarities with <italic>N. drepanophoroides</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Large</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">Friedrich (1957)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes drepanophoroides</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Puget Sound (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Puget Sound (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally reddish and ventrally whitish</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Cephalic organs large, anterior portion opposite ventral commissure; posteriorly between dorsal and ventral<break/>Ganglia, extending behind dorsal ganglia</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">Griffin (1898)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes fernaldi</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B45">Iwata, 2001</xref>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Peavine Pass (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Peavine Pass, Friday Harbor, Willow Island (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">4&#x2013;52 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Gravel bottom; collected by night light in water column</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally pale brown and ventrally lighter in colour; lateral margin transparent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">14</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Very large and extend behind the cerebral ganglia</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B45">Iwata (2001)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ganahai</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Widely found in Japanese coastal waters (off Jogashima, off Ofunato, off Noto, and Tosa Bay)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">71&#x2013;985 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Muddy to sandy substrates mixed with shell debris</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly pale pink to yellow coloured in both dorsal and ventral surface</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes incainca</italic>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Inca-Inca beach (Colombia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Inca-Inca beach and Taganga (Colombia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Under boulders</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly solid bright red coloured</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">Gonzalez-Cueto et&#xa0;al. (2017)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes jambio</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Jogashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">80&#x2013;89 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Muddy to sandy substrates mixed with shell debris</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsal body surface uniformly brownish orange; ventral surface slightly lighter coloured than dorsal surface</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes kozaensis</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koza (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koza (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">12 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among rocky substrates colonized by sponges, ascidians, and bryozoans</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Background generally pale-coloured, mottled with red-brown and white dots; red-brown dots more densely distributed in dorso-anterior region of body; white dots uniformly distributed on both dorsal and ventral surfaces</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes lactea</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Izu (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Izu (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">98&#x2013;120 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among sandy substrates</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly pale in both dorsal and ventral surface</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes madagascarensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer, 1965</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Mozambique Channel (Madagascar)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Mozambique Channel (Madagascar)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among dead encrusting bryozoans covering branches of a coral</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Ochre coloured on dorsal surface mottled with irregular reddish to brown patterns</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">9</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Large cerebral organs extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">Kirsteuer (1965)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes magna</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B71">Punnett, 1903</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pysfjord (Norway)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pysfjord (Norway)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">500 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">On coral bottom (<italic>Lophohelia prolifera</italic> (currently known as <italic>Desmophyllum pertusum</italic>))</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Light orange brown</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">20</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Well developed, extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Punnet (1903); <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes marioni</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">Hubrecht, 1887</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from Marion Island and Christmas Harbor, Kerguelen Island</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Antarctic and Subantarctic waters</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">474 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among kelp holdfasts and on volcanic sands</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">In the original description, only a body diameter was provided: 5.5 mm in maximum; according to <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler (1934)</xref>, body colouration resembles <italic>Amphiporus moseleyi</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">Hubrecht, 1887</xref> (i.e., dorsally blue-green, yellow-green, pale buff or light brown, and ventrally pale buff)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent?</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">15</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Large, extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">Hubrecht (1887)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes neonilae</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Peter the Great Bay (Russia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">East Russian waters including the Sea of Okhotsk and the Sea of Japan</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to 15 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among mytilid beds (<italic>Modiolus kurilensi</italic>, <italic>Crenomytilus grayanus</italic>) and calcareous algae (<italic>Bossiella</italic> sp.)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsally brownish-red or brick-red and ventrally beige or whitish (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4L</bold>
</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present; paired dark coloured triangular patches</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present; mid-dorsal line without reaching to anterior tip of head and not fused with patches</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">16&#x2013;17</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">Chernyshev (1993)</xref>; present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes notoensis</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">70&#x2013;91 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among muddy to sandy substrates</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly pale to pale-yellow coloured</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes occidentalis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Washington (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Washington (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">70&#x2013;190 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">On subtidal pebbles or among muddy substrates mixed with pebbles</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Thickly mottled and blotched with dark reddish brown on a pale ground colour in dorsal surface; ventrally pale coloured</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent?</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ogumai</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B88">Yamaoka, 1947</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Shimoda (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Widely reported from the Pacific coast of Honshu (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to 5 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Under a rock in intertidal to subtidal rocky bottom</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly orange;<break/>the periphery of the ventral surface of the head is edged with a thin, blurred, black line</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">16</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B88">Yamaoka (1947)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al. (2015)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">Abe et&#xa0;al. (2022)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ojimaorum</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koganezaki (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Koganezaki (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">7&#x2013;12 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Subtidally under a rock on sandy substrates</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">dorsal body surface uniformly bright red coloured; ventral surface the same colour as dorsal surface (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4I&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present; mid-longitudinal line not reaching to the anterior end of the cephalic patches, laterally fusing to the cephalic patches, and posteriorly fusing to the dorsal dark colour (Fig. 4J)</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">13</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes ornata</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off Noto (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">70&#x2013;91 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among muddy to sandy substrates</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Background uniformly pale coloured, mottled with white and brown dots; white dots conspicuous in dorsal surface of head region; brown dots more densely distributed in dorso-anterior region of body than ventral and posterior region (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5H&#x2013;J</bold>
</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pacifica</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from the Bering Sea, off Washington, and off central California</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Off central California to the Bering Sea; the<break/>coast of central Chile (Bahia San Vincente)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">70&#x2013;190 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among black sand, broken pebbles, and green muddy substrates mixed with pebbles</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reddish or brownish colour on dorsal surface and pale on ventral surface in a preserved specimen</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent?</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">14</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Cerebral organs remarkably large, extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">Friedrich (1968)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes pulchra</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">Johnston, 1837</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from Berwickshire (UK)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Widely known from the northern hemisphere (North America, Greenland, the Faroe Is., the White Sea and northern Europe, Scandinavia, Mediterranean) as well as the southern hemisphere in Chile, South Africa, Antarctica and<break/>Subantarctica; species identities from these areas not confirmed using molecular data</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to 569 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Under rocks, among sandy to muddy substrates, shell debris, and gravels</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Fresh red coloured (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">Johnston, 1837</xref>); <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref> indicated the body colouration varies by individuals between brown, red and pink.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">8&#x2013;14 (normally 12)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Large, extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">Johnston (1837)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes punctatula</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from Isthmus Cove, Catalina Island (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pacific coast of USA, eastern Russian and Japanese coastal waters (Hokkaido to Nagasaki)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Intertidal to subtidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Under rocks and among algal holdfasts</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Dorsal body surface with a dorsal brown blotch pattern (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4Q, R</bold>
</xref>) or uniformly brownish (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4S, T</bold>
</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12&#x2013;16</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Remarkable voluminous, extending behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B45">Iwata (2001)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B47">Kajihara (2007)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes rubella</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe, 1905</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not designated; originally reported from San Diego and San Pedro (USA)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pacific coasts of USA</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">35&#x2013;200</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among mussels, on rocks or wharf pilings</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Deep fresh colour, pale orange or pale red on dorsal surface; ventrally paler coloured</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">14</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Remarkably highly developed and situated beside and behind the dorsal ganglia</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">Gibson (1995)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes sanguinea</italic> <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser, 1998</xref>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Kakikoura (New Zealand)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Kakikoura (New Zealand)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">intertidal</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Holdfast of <italic>Lessonia variegata</italic> washed up on beach</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Varied from buffy white to pale yellow to<break/>orange, with reddish blood vessels; ventral<break/>surface paler than dorsal; brain lobes pink</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Not evident (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser, 1998</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Elongated, posteriorly reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B73">Riser (1998)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes schollaerti</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler, 1934</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Schollaert Channel, Palmer Archipelago, Antarctica</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Antarctic waters</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">278&#x2013;500 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Pale buff in a living specimen</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">14</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler (1934)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">Berg (1985)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes sugashimaensis</italic> sp. nov.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sugashima (Japan)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">10 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Among subtidal rocky substrates</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Background uniformly pale coloured, with irregular, leopard-like brown mottling</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Present study</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Nipponnemertes variabilis</italic> (Korotkevich, 1983)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Kerguelen Island, Antarctic waters</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Antarctic and subantarctic waters (off the south-eastern coast of South America near Patagonia, north-west of the Falkland Island, off South Africa, and near South Georgia and the Kerguelen Island)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">64&#x2013;295 m</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sandy and muddy substrates, mixed with broken shells and gravels; attached to floating algae</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Beige coloured both dorsally and ventrally</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">12&#x2013;13</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Reaching behind the brain</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B85">Wheeler (1934)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B56">Korotkevitsch (1983)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<italic>Cratenemertes amboiensis</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">B&#xfc;rger, 1890</xref>)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Banda Sea, Ambon (Indonesia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Banda Sea, Ambon (Indonesia)</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Uniformly fresh coloured in both dorsal and ventral surface</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Absent</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">&#x2013;</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Small, almost fused with dorsal ganglia in posterior region</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">B&#xfc;rger (1890)</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B28">Friedrich (1955)</xref>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<p>Apart from relatively small body size in Clade C (see the discussion below), each clade is not characterized by any apparent synapomorphy, but is mutually distinguishable by a combination of three external characters&#x2014;demarcation between the head and body, mid-dorsal ridge on head, and cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). The former two characters are likely plesiomorphic and retained in Clade A (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4</bold>
</xref>) and Clade B (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;5</bold>
</xref>) while the last one is an apomorphy for Clade B (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;4</bold>
</xref>). In members in Clade C, the head is not demarcated from the body and does not have a mid-dorsal ridge and cephalic patches (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f6">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;6</bold>
</xref>). Although it remains unclear in Clade A due to a lack of data, stylet-to-basis-length ratio is also different between Clade B (1.85&#x2013;2.16) and Clade C (1.25&#x2013;1.64) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f7">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;7</bold>
</xref>). Neither clade-specific characters nor combinations of characters are found in internal morphology in the species examined in the present study.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, species in each clade are differentiated by external morphological characters of the head: species possessing demarcated head without cephalic patches (Clade A), demarcated head with cephalic patches (Clade B), and non-demarcated head lacking cephalic patches (Clade C) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). Although the three lineages are presumably characterized by the combination of morphological characters of the head and could be regarded as separate genera, we place all the species in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> since molecular data for the type species, <italic>N. drepanophoroides</italic> is currently unavailable. In possessing heads without cephalic patches, <italic>N. drepanophoroides</italic> is probably included in Clade A rather than Clade C; however, no information is available as to the head&#x2013;trunk demarcation and the mid-dorsal ridge in the original description by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">Griffin (1898)</xref> and redescription by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">Coe (1905)</xref>. Molecular confirmation using topotype specimens is required for future taxonomic reappraisal.</p>
<p>In the present study, greater external morphological disparity between specimens (body coloration and spotting pattern) generally turned out to be a manifestation of species difference with greater phylogenetic/genetic distances (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). However, this was not the case in the <italic>N. kozaensis&#x2013;N. ornata</italic> species pair. Despite having extremely similar body coloration (pale body with reddish to brownish ornamentation; <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;5H&#x2013;J, P, Q</bold>
</xref>), the two did not form a single clade (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). On the contrary, the converse was not true for the &#x201c;<italic>N. ojimaorum</italic>&#x2013;<italic>N. punctatula</italic>&#x201d; subclade in Clade B, consisting of <italic>N. crypta</italic>, <italic>N. jambio</italic>, <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic>, and <italic>N. punctatula</italic>. Their interspecific genetic distances based on COI were 1.6&#x2013;4.4% in uncorrected <italic>p</italic>-distance and (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">
<bold>Table S2</bold>
</xref>), lower than interspecific COI divergences previously reported in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> (3.8&#x2013;4.3% between <italic>N. pulchra</italic> and <italic>N.</italic> cf. <italic>rubella</italic>) (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2022</xref>) and other nemerteans (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B78">Sundberg et&#xa0;al., 2016</xref>). The most conspicuous case was observed between <italic>N. crypta</italic> and <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> showing 1.6% in <italic>p-</italic>distance, albeit apparently different body coloration (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figures&#xa0;4C, D, I&#x2013;K</bold>
</xref>) (similar phenomena have been found in other invertebrates such as bobtail squids (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B26">Fern&#xe1;ndez-&#xc1;lvarez et&#xa0;al., 2021</xref>) and mites (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B31">Garc&#xed;a-Jim&#xe9;nez et&#xa0;al., 2017</xref>). Moreover, the two species were not sister taxa in our tree based on the concatenated dataset (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;2</bold>
</xref>). One thing we can deduce from the result is that the use of COI-based genetic distances might underestimate the true intraspecific divergences due to mutational saturation in COI region among the &#x201c;<italic>N. ojimaorum</italic>&#x2013;<italic>N. punctatula</italic>&#x201d; subclade.</p>
<p>Our species delimitation analyses for Clade B show the consistent result, where five lineages are identified, preferring to separate <italic>N. crypta</italic> and <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> as different species in all three methods (TCS, ABGD, and bPTP) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;3</bold>
</xref>). The threshold used to separate nemertean species based on COI is mostly around 5% (e.g., <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">Chen et&#xa0;al., 2010</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B52">Kang et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B57">Kr&#xe4;mer et&#xa0;al., 2017</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B18">Chernyshev et&#xa0;al., 2018</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B41">Hookabe et&#xa0;al., 2020</xref>). Although the values we obtained were lower than 5%, we describe <italic>N. crypta</italic> and <italic>N. ojimaorum</italic> as separate species based on the differences in body colouration and internal morphology, as well as the result of species delimitation analyses (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>Figure&#xa0;3</bold>
</xref>).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s4_2">
<title>Reduction in Body Size and Blood-Circulatory System in Clade C</title>
<p>The newly confirmed Clade C is formed by relatively smaller species (7&#x2013;20 mm in the maximum body lengths) than the other two clades (12&#x2013;110 mm in Clade A and 11.7&#x2013;160 mm in Clade B) although we could not obtain mature adults for all species in Clade C. The smallest species in Clade C is <italic>N. lactea</italic> with developed gonads. Members in Clade C were collected from subtidal (8 m~) to deep sea bottoms (~985 m). In the deep-sea environment, body-size trends across environmental gradients (hydrostatic pressure, light, water temperature, and amount of food resources) have been demonstrated in invertebrates and demersal fish (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B23">Collins et&#xa0;al., 2005</xref>). It is difficult to determine which variable(s) most critically influences body size; still, food availability is known as one the of major factors in these animals (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B23">Collins et&#xa0;al., 2005</xref>). The body size reduction in Clade C in contrast with Clade A and B might reflect an adaptation to food-limitation in deep-water bottoms (herein referring to water depths deeper than 70 m) as inferred in non-scavenging fish (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B23">Collins et&#xa0;al., 2005</xref>) or predatory invertebrates (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B84">Van der Grient &amp; Rogers, 2015</xref>). If species in Clade C are suctorial predators on small crustaceans as reported in <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> cf. <italic>africana</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B67">McDermott, 1997</xref>), <italic>N. pulchra</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6">Brunberg, 1964</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">Berg, 1972</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B65">McDermott, 1984</xref>, 1993), and <italic>N. ogumai</italic> (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">Kajihara et&#xa0;al., 2015</xref>), smaller body sizes might allow them to require less food demand for survival and reproduction. The phylogenetic positions among Clade C also indicate that <italic>N. kozaensis</italic> collected at a depth of 12 m, <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic> collected at a depth of 10 m, and Cratenemertidae sp. Guam collected at a depth of 1 m (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">Chernyshev &amp; Polyakova, 2019</xref>) might have secondarily colonized from deep (&gt;70 m) to shallow waters (&lt;12 m). Since ecological factors other than amount of potential food resources can be also related to the body size evolution, the speculation above should be accompanied with further examination of ecological data on species collected from various water depths.</p>
<p>The vascular plug, by which nutrients and other substances are supposedly delivered from the blood vascular system to the rhynchocoel (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B24">Crandall, 1993</xref>), is considered to be important to maintain the function of proboscis apparatus principally used to capture prey items. In small-bodied hoplonemerteans, in contrast, this structure seems to have been often lost, suggesting that the proboscis could function without a vascular plug by diffusion through the rhynchocoel wall (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">Kajihara, 2021b</xref>). In Clade C, a vascular plug is not observed except for <italic>N. sugashimaensis</italic>. This might be actually resulted from a small body size; however, the other possibility is that a vascular plug is easily affected by body contraction during fixation and/or difficult to find through histological sectioning in small-sized species. Additional morphological examination with broader taxon sampling as well as alternative methods for observation of the fine muscular structure (e.g., phalloidin labelling) is expected in future studies.</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="s5" sec-type="data-availability">
<title>Data Availability Statement</title>
<p>The datasets presented in this study can be found in online repositories. The names of the repository/repositories and accession number(s) can be found in the article/<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM2">
<bold>Supplementary Material</bold>
</xref>.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s6" sec-type="author-contributions">
<title>Author Contributions</title>
<p>NHo conceived the present study, executed molecular experiments, and analyzed the molecular data. NHo, HKa, and AC performed morphological observation and analyzed morphological data. All authors took part in the collection of animal samples and field data used in this study. The manuscript was drafted by NHo and critically reviewed by the other authors. All authors approved the final manuscript for submission and publication.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s7" sec-type="funding-information">
<title>Funding</title>
<p>Part of this study was supported by the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (21J14807 for NHo; 25650133, 26282067, 26304011, 20H03304, 20K06780 for HKa).</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s8" sec-type="COI-statement">
<title>Conflict of Interest</title>
<p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p>
<p>The reviewer AV declared a past collaboration with one of the authors HKa to the handling Editor</p>
</sec>
<sec id="s9" sec-type="disclaimer">
<title>Publisher&#x2019;s Note</title>
<p>All claims expressed in this article are solely those of the authors and do not necessarily represent those of their affiliated organizations, or those of the publisher, the editors and the reviewers. Any product that may be evaluated in this article, or claim that may be made by its manufacturer, is not guaranteed or endorsed by the publisher.</p>
</sec>
</body>
<back>
<ack>
<title>Acknowledgments</title>
<p>NHo and HKa thank Mamoru Sekifuji, Michiyo Kawabata (Misaki Marine Biological Station, the University of Tokyo) for help in collecting samples off Jogashima and Hiroaki Nakano (Shimoda Marine Research Center, University of Tsukuba) for organizing JAMBIO Coastal Organism Joint Surveys. NHo also thank Shouzo Ogiso (Noto Marine Laboratory, Kanazawa University) and the all the other participants in the 22nd JAMBIO Coastal Organism Joint Surveys in Noto. NHo, NJ, ST, and YF are thankful to Kensuke Yanagi (Natural History Museum and Institute, Chiba) and all the other participants in the Tohoku Ecosystem-Associated Marine Sciences (TEAMS) research project for generous help in sample collection; the captain and the crew of R/V <italic>Kaimei</italic> during KM19-05C cruise. NHo, NJ, and KT thank Hironori Komatsu (National Museum of Nature and Science, Tokyo (NSMT)), Akito Ogawa (JAMSTEC), Itaru Kobayashi, Gregorius Altius Pratama, Takumi Matsuo (the University of Tokyo) for help in sample collection in Shimoda. NHo thanks Ryuta Yoshida (Marine and Coastal Research Center, Ochanomizu University) for sincerely providing specimens used in this study with NHo. NHo, NJ, and MO are grateful to Masanori Kawai, Tomohito Ojima, Masako Ojima, Masanori Taru (Tokyo Bay Ecosystem Research Center, Toho University), and Hiroyuki Yokooka (Institute of Environmental Ecology, IDEA Consultants, Inc.) for sincere help in collecting specimens in Koganezaki. NHo, NJ, and NHa thank Takeo Sugimoto (South Wakayama Fishery Cooperative), Naofumi Ueda, Takashi Okada, Ayumi Mizutani (DIVE KOOZA) and Cati (Association for the Protection of the Sea and Marine Life, Umimorinchu) during sampling in Wakayama. Special thanks to Masashi Fukuoka, Maki Shirae-Kurabayashi, and Gohta Goshima (Sugashima Marine Biological Laboratory, Nagoya University) for kindly helping in sample collection as well as providing facilities during NHo&#x2019;s sampling trip. NHo thanks Hiroshi Namikawa (NSMT), Hiroshi Saito (NSMT), Keiichi Kakui, Yuki Oya (Hokkaido University), Itaru Kobayashi (the University of Tokyo), Tomomi Saito, and Kouki Tanaka (Kochi University) for their generous help during sampling in Tosa Bay. This study was supported by the research project Tohoku Ecosystem-Associated Marine Sciences from the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology and National Museum of Nature and Science integrated research on &#x201c;Geological, biological, and anthropological histories in relation to the Kuroshio Current&#x201d;.</p>
</ack>
<sec id="s10" sec-type="supplementary-material">
<title>Supplementary Material</title>
<p>The Supplementary Material for this article can be found online at: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmars.2022.906383/full#supplementary-material">https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fmars.2022.906383/full#supplementary-material</ext-link>
</p>
<supplementary-material xlink:href="DataSheet_1.docx" id="SM1" mimetype="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
<supplementary-material xlink:href="Image_1.jpeg" id="SM2" mimetype="image/jpeg"/>
</sec>
<ref-list>
<title>References</title>
<ref id="B1">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Abe</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kan</surname> <given-names>K.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Matsumasa</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Suzuki</surname> <given-names>T.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2022</year>). <source>
<italic>Northernmost Record of</italic> Nipponnemertes ogumai <italic>(Nemertea: Monostilifera)</italic> in Otomo-Ura</source> (<publisher-loc>Iwate Prefecture, Japan</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Michi. Ben</publisher-name>), <fpage>6</fpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B2">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Andrade</surname> <given-names>S. C. S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Strand</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Schwartz</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Chen</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Sun</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Disentangling Ribbon Worm Relationships: Multi-Locus Analysis Supports Traditional Classification on the Phylum Nemertea</article-title>. <source>Cladistics</source> <volume>28</volume>, <fpage>141</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>159</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1096-0031.2011.00376.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B3">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Berg</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1972</year>). <article-title>Studies on <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> Friedrich 1968 (Nemertini, Hoplonemertini) I. Redescription of <italic>Nipponnemertes pulcher</italic> (Johnston 1837) With Special Reference to Intraspecific Variation of the Taxonomical Characters</article-title>. <source>Zool. Scr.</source> <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>211</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>225</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1463-6409.1972.tb00580.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B4">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Berg</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1985</year>). <article-title>Studies on <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> Friedrich (Nemertini, Hoplonemertini). II. Taxonomy of <italic>Nipponnemertes pulcher</italic> (Johnston) and Some Other Species</article-title>. <source>Zool. Scr.</source> <volume>14</volume>, <fpage>239</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>246</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1463-6409.1985.tb00194.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B5">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Brinkmann</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1914&#x2013;1915</year>). <article-title>
<italic>Uniporus</italic>, Ein Neues Genus Der Familie Drepanophoridae Verrill</article-title>. <source>Ber. Mus. Aar.</source> <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>29</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B6">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Brunberg</surname> <given-names>L.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1964</year>). <article-title>On the Nemertean Fauna of Danish Waters</article-title>. <source>Ophelia</source> <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>77</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>111</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00785326.1964.10416273</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B7">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>B&#xfc;rger</surname> <given-names>O.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1890</year>). <article-title>Untersuchungen &#xfc;ber die Anatomie und Histologie der Nemertinen nebst Beitr&#xe4;gen zur Systematik</article-title>. <source>Z. Wiss. Zool.</source> <volume>50</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>277</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B8">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Castresana</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2000</year>). <article-title>Selection of Conserved Blocks From Multiple Alignments for Their Use in Phylogenetic Analysis</article-title>. <source>Mol. Biol. Evol.</source> <volume>17</volume>, <fpage>540</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>552</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.molbev.a026334</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B9">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chen</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Strand</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Norenburg</surname> <given-names>J. L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Sun</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Statistical Parsimony Networks and Species Assemblages in Cephalotrichid Nemerteans (Nemertea)</article-title>. <source>PloS One</source> <volume>5</volume>, <elocation-id>e12885</elocation-id>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012885</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B10">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1993</year>). <article-title>Novuie Svedeniya O Sistematike Nemertin Semeistva Cratenemertidae (Enopla, Monostilifera)</article-title>. <source>Vest. Zool.</source> <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>72</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>75</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B11">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Confocal laser scanning microscopy analysis of the phalloidin-labelled musculature in nemerteans</article-title>. <source>J. Nat. Hist.</source> <volume>44</volume>, <fpage>2287</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>2302</lpage>. </citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B12">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2016</year>). &#x201c;<article-title>Nemerteans of the Coastal Waters of Vietnam</article-title>&#x201d;, in <source>Biodiversity of the Western Part of the South China Sea</source>. Eds. <person-group person-group-type="editor">
<name>
<surname>Adrianov</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Lutaenko</surname> <given-names>K. A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<publisher-loc>Vladivostok, RU</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Dalnauka</publisher-name>), <fpage>279</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>314</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B13">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans From the Far Eastern Seas of Russia</article-title>. <source>Russ. J. Mar. Biol.</source> <volume>46</volume>, <fpage>141</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>153</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1134/S1063074020030049</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B14">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>An Updated Classification of the Phylum Nemertea</article-title>. <source>Invertebrate. Zool.</source> <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>188</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>196</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.15298/invertzool.18.3.01</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B15">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Polyakova</surname> <given-names>N. E.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans of the Vema-TRANSIT Expedition: First Data on Diversity With Description of Two New Genera and Species</article-title>. <source>Deep-Sea. Res. II.: Top. Stud. Oceanogr.</source> <volume>148</volume>, <fpage>64</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>73</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.dsr2.2017.06.004</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B16">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Polyakova</surname> <given-names>N. E.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans From the Deep-Sea Expedition KuramBio II With Descriptions of Three New Hoplonemerteans From the Kuril-Kamchatka Trench</article-title>. <source>Prog. Oceanogr.</source> <volume>178</volume>, <fpage>102</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>148</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.pocean.2019.102148</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B17">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Polyakova</surname> <given-names>N. E.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2022</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans Collected in the Bering Sea During the Research Cruises Aboard the R/V Akademik MA Lavrentyev in 2016, 2018, and 2021 With an Analysis of Deep-Sea Heteronemertean and Hoplonemertean Species</article-title>. <source>Deep. Sea. Res. Part II. Top. Stud. Oceanogr.</source>, <volume>199</volume>, <fpage>105081</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.dsr2.2022.105081</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B18">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Polyakova</surname> <given-names>N. E.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Turanov</surname> <given-names>S. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>Taxonomy and Phylogeny of <italic>Lineus torquatus</italic> and Allies (Nemertea, Lineidae) With Descriptions of a New Genus and a New Cryptic Species</article-title>. <source>Syst. Biodiv.</source> <volume>16</volume>, <fpage>55</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>68</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/14772000.2017.1317672</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B19">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Clement</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Posada</surname> <given-names>D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names>K. A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2000</year>). <article-title>TCS: A Computer Program to Estimate Gene Genealogies</article-title>. <source>Mol. Ecol.</source> <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>1657</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1659</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1365-294x.2000.01020.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B20">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Coe</surname> <given-names>W. R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1901</year>). <article-title>Papers From the Harriman Alaska Expedition. XX. The Nemerteans</article-title>. <source>Proc. Wash. Acad. Sci.</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>110</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B21">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Coe</surname> <given-names>W. R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1905</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans of the West and Northwest Coasts of America</article-title>. <source>Bull. Mus. Comp. Zool.</source> <volume>47</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>318</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B22">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Colgan</surname> <given-names>D. J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>McLauchlan</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Wilson</surname> <given-names>G. D. F.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Livingston</surname> <given-names>S. P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Edgecombe</surname> <given-names>G. D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Macaranas</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. (<year>1998</year>). <article-title>Histone H3 and U2 snRNA DNA Sequences and Arthropod Molecular Evolution</article-title>. <source>Aust. J. Zool.</source> <volume>46</volume>, <fpage>419</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>437</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1071/ZO98048</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B23">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Collins</surname> <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Bailey</surname> <given-names>D. M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Ruxton</surname> <given-names>G. D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Priede</surname> <given-names>I. G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>Trends in Body Size Across an Environmental Gradient: A Differential Response in Scavenging and non-Scavenging Demersal Deep-Sea Fish</article-title>. <source>Proc. R. Soc B.: Biol. Sci.</source> <volume>272</volume>, <fpage>2051</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>2057</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B24">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names>F. B.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1993</year>). <article-title>Major Characters and Enoplan Systematics</article-title>. <source>Hydrobiologia</source> <volume>266</volume>, <fpage>115</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>140</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00013363</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B25">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names>F. B.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names> J. L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Maslakova</surname> <given-names>S. A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Schwartz &amp; H. Kajihara</surname> <given-names>M. L.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2002</year>). <article-title>Checklist of the nemertean fauna of Japan and northeastern Asia</article-title>. <publisher-loc>Washington D.C</publisher-loc>:<publisher-name>Smithsonian Institution</publisher-name>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>44</lpage>. Available from <uri xlink:href="http://pages.uoregon.edu/svetlana/Crandall2002.pdf">http://pages.uoregon.edu/svetlana/Crandall2002.pdf</uri> </citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B26">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Fern&#xe1;ndez-&#xc1;lvarez</surname> <given-names>F.&#xc1;.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>S&#xe1;nchez</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Villanueva</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>Morphological and Molecular Assessments of Bobtail Squids (Cephalopoda: Sepiolidae) Reveal a Hidden History of Biodiversity</article-title>. <source>Front. Mar. Sci.</source> <volume>7</volume>, <elocation-id>632261</elocation-id>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fmars.2020.632261</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B27">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Folmer</surname> <given-names>O.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Black</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Hoeh</surname> <given-names>W.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Lutz</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Vrijenhoek</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <article-title>DNA Primers for Amplification of Mitochondrial Cytochrome <italic>C</italic> Oxidase Subunit I From Diverse Metazoan Invertebrates</article-title>. <source>Mol. Mar. Biol. Biotechnol.</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>294</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>299</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B28">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Friedrich</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1955</year>). <article-title>Beitr&#xe4;ge Zu Einer Synopsis Der Gattungen Der Nemertini Monostilifera Nebst Bestimmungsschl&#xfc;ssel</article-title>. <source>Z. Wiss. Zool.</source> <volume>158</volume>, <fpage>133</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>192</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B29">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Friedrich</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1957</year>). <article-title>Beitr&#xe4;ge Zur Kenntnis Der Arktischen Hoplonemertinen</article-title>. <source>Vidensk. Meddel. Natuirist. Foren. Kjobenhavn.</source> <volume>119</volume>, <fpage>129</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>154</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B30">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Friedrich</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1968</year>). <article-title>
<italic>Sagaminemertes</italic>, Eine Bemerkenswerte Neue Gattung Der Hoplonemertinen Und Ihre Systematische Stellung</article-title>. <source>Zool. Anz.</source> <volume>180</volume>, <fpage>33</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>36</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B31">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Garc&#xed;a-Jim&#xe9;nez</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Horreo</surname> <given-names>J. L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Valdecasas</surname> <given-names>A. G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Minimal Barcode Distance Between Two Water Mite Species From Madeira Island: A Cautionary Tale</article-title>. <source>Exp. Appl. Acarol.</source> <volume>72</volume>, <fpage>133</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>143</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10493-017-0147-5</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B32">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Gering</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1912</year>). <article-title>Neue Nemertinen Der Schwedischen Westk&#xfc;ste</article-title>. <source>Zool. Anz.</source> <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>520</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>523</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B33">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Gibson</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <source>Nemerteans</source> (<publisher-loc>Shrewsbury</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Field Studies Council</publisher-name>).</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B34">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Gibson</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1995</year>). <article-title>Nemertean Genera and Species of the World: An Annotated Checklist of Original Names and Description Citations, Synonyms, Current Taxonomic Status, Habitats and Recorded Zoogeographic Distribution</article-title>. <source>J. Nat. Hist.</source> <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>271</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>562</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00222939500770161</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B35">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Gibson</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names>F. B.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1989</year>). <article-title>The Genus <italic>Amphiporus</italic> Ehrenberg (Nemertea, Enopla, Monostiliferoidea)</article-title>. <source>Zool. Scr.</source> <volume>18</volume>, <fpage>453</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>470</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1463-6409.1989.tb00140.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B36">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Giribet</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Carranza</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Bagu&#xf1;&#xe0;</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Riutort</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Ribera</surname> <given-names>C.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1996</year>). <article-title>First Molecular Evidence for the Existence of a Tardigrada + Arthropoda Clade</article-title>. <source>Mol. Biol. Evol.</source> <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>76</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>84</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.molbev.a025573</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B37">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Gonzalez-Cueto</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Castro</surname> <given-names>L. R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Quiroga</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>
<italic>Nipponnemertes incainca</italic> sp. n. Adoption of the New Taxonomic Proposal for Nemerteans (Nemertea, Cratenemertidae)</article-title>. <source>ZooKeys</source> <volume>693</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>15</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3897/zookeys.693.12015</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B38">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Griffin</surname> <given-names>B. B.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1898</year>). <article-title>Description of Some Marine Nemerteans of Puget Sound and Alaska</article-title>. <source>Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci.</source> <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>193</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>217</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1898.tb54969.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B39">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Hillis</surname> <given-names>D. M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Dixon</surname> <given-names>M. T.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1991</year>). <article-title>Ribosomal DNA: Molecular Evolution and Phylogenetic Inference</article-title>. <source>Q. Rev. Biol.</source> <volume>66</volume>, <fpage>411</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>453</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1086/417338</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B40">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Hookabe</surname> <given-names>N.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kohtsuka</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>A Histology-Free Description of <italic>Tetrastemma cupido</italic> sp. nov. (Nemertea: Eumonostilfera) From Sagami Bay, Japan</article-title>. <source>Mar. Biol. Res.</source> <volume>17</volume>, <fpage>467</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>474</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/17451000.2021.1979236</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B41">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Hookabe</surname> <given-names>N.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Tsuchida</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Fujiwara</surname> <given-names>Y.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>A New Species of Bathyal Nemertean, <italic>Proamphiporus kaimeiae</italic> sp. nov., Off Tohoku, Japan, and Molecular Systematics of the Genus (Nemertea: Monostilifera)</article-title>. <source>Spec. Div.</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>183</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>188</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.12782/specdiv.25.183</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B42">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Hubrecht</surname> <given-names>A. A. W.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1887</year>). <article-title>Report on the Nemertea Collected by H.M.S. Challenger During the Years 1873&#x2013;76</article-title>. <source>Rep. Sci. Res. Chall.</source> <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>150</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B43">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<collab>International Commission on Zoological Nomenclature</collab>
</person-group> (<year>1999</year>). <source>International Code of Zoological Nomenclature</source>. <edition>4th Edition</edition> (<publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>International Trust for Zoological Nomenclature</publisher-name>).</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B44">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Iwata</surname> <given-names>F.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1954</year>). <article-title>The Fauna of Akkeshi Bay. XX. Nemertini in Hokkaido (Revised Report)</article-title>. <source>J. Fac. Sci. Hokkaido. Univ. 6 Zool.</source> <volume>12</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>39</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B45">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Iwata</surname> <given-names>F.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2001</year>). <article-title>
<italic>Nipponnemertes fernaldi</italic>, a New Species of Swimming Monostiliferous Hoplonemertean From the San Juan Archipelago, Washington, USA</article-title>. <source>Proc. Biol. Soc Wash.</source> <volume>114</volume>, <fpage>833</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>857</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B46">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Johnston</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1837</year>). <article-title>Miscellanea Zoologica. II. A Description of Some Planarian Worms</article-title>. <source>Mag. Zool. Bot.</source> <volume>1</volume>, <fpage>529</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>538</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B47">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>A Taxonomic Catalogue of Japanese Nemerteans (Phylum Nemertea)</article-title>. <source>Zool. Sci.</source> <volume>24</volume>, <fpage>287</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>326</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2108/zsj.24.287</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B48">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2017</year>). &#x201c;<article-title>Species Diversity of Japanese Ribbon Worms (Nemertea)</article-title>&#x201d; in <source>Species Diversity of Animals in Japan</source>. Eds. <person-group person-group-type="editor">
<name>
<surname>Motokawa</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<publisher-loc>Tokyo</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Springer Japan</publisher-name>), <fpage>419</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>444</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B49">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2021</year>a). &#x201c;<article-title>Phylum Nemertea"</article-title> in <source>Invertebrate Zoology. A Tree of Life Approach</source>. Eds. <person-group person-group-type="editor">
<name>
<surname>Schierwater</surname> <given-names>B.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>DeSalle</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<publisher-loc>Boca Raton</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>CRC Press</publisher-name>), <fpage>357</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>368</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B50">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2021</year>b). <article-title>Higher Classification of the Monostilifera (Nemertea: Hoplonemertea)</article-title>. <source>Zootaxa</source> <volume>4920</volume>, <fpage>151</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>199</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.11646/zootaxa.4920.2.1</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B51">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kajihara</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Nishi</surname> <given-names>E.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kawabata</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kohtsuka</surname> <given-names>H.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Uyeno</surname> <given-names>D.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Records of the Poorly Known Ribbon Worm <italic>Nipponnemertes ogumai</italic> (Nemertea: Monostilifera) and its Phylogenetic Position</article-title>. <source>Mar. Biodiv.</source> <volume>45</volume>, <fpage>175</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>182</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12526-014-0252-1</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B52">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kang</surname> <given-names>X. X.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Fern&#xe1;ndez-&#xc1;lvarez</surname> <given-names>F.&#xc1;.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Alfaya</surname> <given-names>J. E.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Machordom</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Strand</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Sundberg</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Species Diversity of <italic>Ramphogordius sanguineus</italic>/<italic>Lineus ruber-</italic>Like Nemerteans (Nemertea: Heteronemertea) and Geographic Distribution of</article-title>. <source>R. sanguineus Zool. Sci.</source> <volume>32</volume>, <fpage>579</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>589</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2108/zs150064</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B53">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Katoh</surname> <given-names>K.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Standley</surname> <given-names>D. M.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>MAFFT Multiple Sequence Alignment Software Version 7: Improvements in Performance and Usability</article-title>. <source>Mol. Biol. Evol.</source> <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>772</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>780</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/molbev/mst010</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B54">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kirsteuer</surname> <given-names>E.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1965</year>). <article-title>&#xdc;ber Das Vorkommen Von Nemertinen in Einem Tropischen Korallenriff. 4. Hoplonemertini Monostilifera</article-title>. <source>Zool. Jahrb. Abt. Syst. Geog. Biol. Tiere.</source> <volume>92</volume>, <fpage>289</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>326</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B55">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Korotkevitsch</surname> <given-names>V. S.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1961</year>). <article-title>A New Nemertean Species and its Position in the System</article-title>. <source>Zool. Zhurnal.</source> <volume>40</volume>, <fpage>1416</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1420</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B56">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Korotkevitsch</surname> <given-names>V. S.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1983</year>). <article-title>O Stiletakh Nemertin I Novom Vide <italic>Cratenemertes</italic> (Hoplonemertini, Amphiporidae) Iz Antarktiki</article-title>. <source>Antark. Dok. Kom.</source> <volume>22</volume>, <fpage>137</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>143</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B57">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kr&#xe4;mer</surname> <given-names>D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Schmidt</surname> <given-names>C.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Podsiadlowski</surname> <given-names>L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Beckers</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Horn</surname> <given-names>L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>D&#xf6;hren</surname> <given-names>J.v.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Unravelling the <italic>Lineus ruber</italic>/<italic>viridis</italic> Species Complex (Nemertea, Heteronemertea)</article-title>. <source>Zool. Scr.</source> <volume>46</volume>, <fpage>111</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>126</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/zsc.12185</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B58">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kumar</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Stecher</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Tamura</surname> <given-names>K.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>MEGA7: Molecular Evolutionary Genetics Analysis Version 7.0 for Bigger Datasets</article-title>. <source>Mol. Biol. Evol.</source> <volume>33</volume>, <fpage>1870</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1874</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/molbev/msw054</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B59">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kvist</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Chernyshev</surname> <given-names>A. V.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Giribet</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Phylogeny of Nemertea With Special Interest in the Placement of Diversity From Far East Russia and Northeast Asia</article-title>. <source>Hydrobiologia</source> <volume>760</volume>, <fpage>105</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>119</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10750-015-2310-5</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B60">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Kvist</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Laumer</surname> <given-names>C. E.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Junoy</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Giribet</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>New Insights Into the Phylogeny, Systematics and DNA Barcoding of Nemertea</article-title>. <source>Invert. Syst.</source> <volume>28</volume>, <fpage>287</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>308</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1071/IS13061</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B61">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Lanfear</surname> <given-names>R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Frandsen</surname> <given-names>P. B.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Wright</surname> <given-names>A. M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Senfeld</surname> <given-names>T.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Calcott</surname> <given-names>B.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>PartitionFinder 2: New Methods for Selecting Partitioned Models of Evolution for Molecular and Morphological Phylogenetic Analyses</article-title>. <source>Mol. Biol. Evol.</source> <volume>34</volume>, <fpage>772</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>773</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/molbev/msw260</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B62">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Leasi</surname> <given-names>F.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Andrade</surname> <given-names>S. D. S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Norenburg</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>At Least Some Meiofaunal Species are Not Everywhere. Indication of Geographic, Ecological and Geological Barriers Affecting the Dispersion of Species of <italic>Ototyphlonemertes</italic> (Nemertea, Hoplonemertea)</article-title>. <source>Mol. Ecol.</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>1381</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1397</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/mec.13568</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B63">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Leigh</surname> <given-names>J. W.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Bryant</surname> <given-names>D.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Popart: Full-Feature Software for Haplotype Network Construction</article-title>. <source>Methods Ecol. Evol.</source> <volume>6</volume>, <fpage>1110</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1116</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.12410</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B64">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Littlewood</surname> <given-names>D. T. J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <article-title>Molecular Phylogenetics of Cupped Oysters Based on Partial 28S rRNA Gene Sequences</article-title>. <source>Mol. Phylogenet. Evol.</source> <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>221</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>229</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/mpev.1994.1024</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B65">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>McDermott</surname> <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1984</year>). <article-title>The Feeding Biology of <italic>Nipponnemertes pulcher</italic> (Johnston) (Hoplonemertea), With Some Ecological Implications</article-title>. <source>Ophelia</source> <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>21</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00785236.1984.10426601</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B66">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>McDermott</surname> <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1993</year>). <article-title>Nemertea Inhabiting the <italic>Haploops</italic> (Amphipoda) Community of the Northern &#xd8;resund With Special Reference to the Biology of <italic>Nipponnemertes pulcher</italic> (Hoplonemertea)</article-title>. <source>Hydrobiologia</source> <volume>266</volume>, <fpage>15</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>28</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00013356</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B67">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>McDermott</surname> <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1997</year>). <article-title>Observations on Feeding in a South African Suctorial Hoplonemertean, <italic>Nipponnemertes</italic> sp. (Family Cratenemertidae)</article-title>. <source>Hydrobiologia</source> <volume>365</volume>, <fpage>251</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>256</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/A:1003114117397</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B68">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>McDermott</surname> <given-names>J. J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Roe</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1985</year>). <article-title>Food, Feeding Behavior and Feeding Ecology of Nemerteans</article-title>. <source>Am. Zool.</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>113</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>125</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/icb/25.1.113</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B69">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Palumbi</surname> <given-names>S. R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Martin</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Romano</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>McMillan</surname> <given-names>W. O.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Stice</surname> <given-names>L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Grabowski</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1991</year>). <source>The Simple Fool&#x2019;s Guide to PCR, V. 2.0</source> (<publisher-loc>Honolulu</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Department Zoology, Kewalo Marine Laboratory, University of Hawaii</publisher-name>).</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B70">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Puillandre</surname> <given-names>N.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Lambert</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Brouillet</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Achaz</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>ABGD, Automatic Barcode Gap Discovery for Primary Species Delimitation</article-title>. <source>Mol. Ecol.</source> <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>1864</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1877</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-294X.2011.05239.x</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B71">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Punnett</surname> <given-names>R. C.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1903</year>). <article-title>On the Nemerteans of Norway</article-title>. <source>Ber. Mus. Aarbog.</source> <volume>2</volume>, <fpage>3</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>35</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B72">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Rambaut</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Drummond</surname> <given-names>A. J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Xie</surname> <given-names>D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Baele</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Suchard</surname> <given-names>M. A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>Posterior Summarisation in Bayesian Phylogenetics Using Tracer Ver. 1.7</article-title>. <source>Syst. Biol.</source> <volume>67</volume>, <fpage>901</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>904</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/sysbio/syy032</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B73">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Riser</surname> <given-names>N. W.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1998</year>). <article-title>New Zealand Nemertines From Kelp Holdfasts: Hoplonemertinea 1. <italic>Nipponnemertes sanguinea</italic> sp</article-title>. <source>N. Z. J. Zool.</source> <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>287</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>294</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/03014223.1998.9518157</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B74">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Ronquist</surname> <given-names>F.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Teslenko</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>van der Mark</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Ayres</surname> <given-names>D. L.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Darling</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>H&#xf6;hna</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>MrBayes 3.2: Efficient Bayesian Phylogenetic Inference and Model Choice Across a Large Model Space</article-title>. <source>Syst. Biol.</source> <volume>61</volume>, <fpage>539</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>542</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/sysbio/sys029</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B75">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Schwendinger</surname> <given-names>P. J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Giribet</surname> <given-names>G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>The Systematics of the Southeast Asian Genus <italic>Fangensis</italic> Rambla (Opiliones: Cyphophthalmi: Stylocellidae)</article-title>. <source>Invert. Syst.</source> <volume>19</volume>, <fpage>297</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>323</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1071/IS05023</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B76">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Stamatakis</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>RAxML Version 8: A Tool for Phylogenetic Analysis and Post-Analysis of Large Phylogenies</article-title>. <source>Bioinformatics</source> <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>1312</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>1313</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btu033</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B77">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Stimpson</surname> <given-names>W.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1857</year>). <article-title>Prodromus Descriptionis Animalium Evertebratorum, Quae in Expeditione ad Oceanum Pacificum Septentrionalem,a Republica Federata missa, Cadwaladaro Ringgold et Johanne Rodgers Ducibus, observavit et descripsit. ParsII. Turbellarieorum Nemertineorum</article-title>.. <source>Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia</source> <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>159</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>165</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B78">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Sundberg</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kvist</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Strand</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Evaluating the Utility of Single-Locus DNA Barcoding for the Identification of Ribbon Worms (Phylum Nemertea)</article-title>. <source>PloS One</source> <volume>1</volume>, <elocation-id>e0155541</elocation-id>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0155541</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B79">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Templeton</surname> <given-names>A. R.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Crandall</surname> <given-names>K. A.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Sing</surname> <given-names>C. F.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1992</year>). <article-title>A Cladistic Analysis of Phenotypic Associations With Haplotypes Inferred From Restriction Endonuclease Mapping and DNA Sequence Data. III. Cladogram Estimation</article-title>. <source>Genetics</source> <volume>132</volume>, <fpage>619</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>633</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B80">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Thiel</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kruse</surname> <given-names>I.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2001</year>). <article-title>Status of the Nemertea as Predators in Marine Ecosystems</article-title>. <source>Hydrobiologia</source> <volume>456</volume>, <fpage>21</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>32</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/A:1013005814145</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B81">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Thollesson</surname> <given-names>M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Norenburg</surname> <given-names>J. L.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Ribbon Worm Relationships: A Phylogeny of the Phylum Nemertea</article-title>. <source>Proc. R. Soc. B: Biol. Sci.</source> <volume>270</volume>, <fpage>407</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>415</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1098/rspb.2002.2254</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B82">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Thompson</surname> <given-names>J. D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Higgins</surname> <given-names>D. G.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Gibson</surname> <given-names>T. J.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <article-title>CLUSTAL W: Improving the Sensitivity of Progressive Multiple Sequence Alignment Through Sequence Weighting, Position-Specific Gap Penalties and Weight Matrix Choice</article-title>. <source>Nucleic Acids Res.</source> <volume>22</volume>, <fpage>4673</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>4680</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/nar/22.22.4673</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B83">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Ushakov</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1927</year>). <article-title>Eine Neue Nemertine Des Japanischen Meeres</article-title>. <source>Zool. Anz.</source> <volume>72</volume>, <fpage>289</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>290</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B84">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Van der Grient</surname> <given-names>J. M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Rogers</surname> <given-names>A. D.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Body Size Versus Depth: Regional and Taxonomical Variation in Deep-Sea Meio-And Macrofaunal Organisms</article-title>. <source>Adv. Mar. Biol.</source> <volume>71</volume>, <fpage>71</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>108</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/bs.amb.2015.07.002</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B85">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Wheeler</surname> <given-names>J. F. G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1934</year>). <article-title>Nemerteans From the South Atlantic and Southern Oceans</article-title>. <source>&#x2018;Discovery&#x2019;. Rep</source> <volume>9</volume>, <fpage>215</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>294</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B86">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Wheeler</surname> <given-names>J. F. G.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1940</year>). <article-title>Some Nemerteans from South Africa and a Note on <italic>Lineus corrugatus</italic> McIntosh</article-title>. <source>Zool. J. Linn. Soc.</source> <volume>41</volume>, <fpage>20</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>49</lpage>.</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B87">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Whiting</surname> <given-names>M. F.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Carpenter</surname> <given-names>J. M.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Wheeler</surname> <given-names>Q. D.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Wheeler</surname> <given-names>W. C.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1997</year>). <article-title>The Strepsiptera Problem: Phylogeny of the Holometabolous Insect Orders Inferred From 18S and 28S Ribosomal DNA Sequences and Morphology</article-title>. <source>Syst. Biol.</source> <volume>46</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>68</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/sysbio/46.1.1</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B88">
<citation citation-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Yamaoka</surname> <given-names>T.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>1947</year>). <article-title>&#x201c;<italic>Amphiporus ogumai</italic>&#x201d;</article-title>, in <source>Revised Edition, Illustrated Encyclopedia of the Fauna of Japan (Exclusive of Insects)</source>. Ed. <person-group person-group-type="editor">
<name>
<surname>Okuda</surname> <given-names>S.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<publisher-loc>Tokyo</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Hokuryukan</publisher-name>). 1468, fig. 4138 (1&#x2013;3).</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B89">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Yamaoka</surname> <given-names>T.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>On Fourteen Monostiliferous Hoplonemerteans From the Izu Peninsula, Middle Japan</article-title>. <source>Publ. Seto. Mar. Biol. Lab.</source> <volume>40</volume>, <fpage>141</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>158</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5134/176324</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
<ref id="B90">
<citation citation-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name>
<surname>Zhang</surname> <given-names>J.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Kapli</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Pavlidis</surname> <given-names>P.</given-names>
</name>
<name>
<surname>Stamatakis</surname> <given-names>A.</given-names>
</name>
</person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>A General Species Delimitation Method With Applications to Phylogenetic Placements</article-title>. <source>Bioinformatics</source> <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>2869</fpage>&#x2013;<lpage>2876</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btt499</pub-id>
</citation>
</ref>
</ref-list>
</back>
</article>